<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Onset-based Sound Segmentation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Leslie</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">CCCN jDepartment of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Stirling</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>FK9 4LA</postCode>
									<settlement>Stirling</settlement>
									<country key="GB">Scotland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Onset-based Sound Segmentation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A technique for segmenting sounds using processing based on mam-malian early auditory processing is presented. The technique is based on features in sound which neuron spike recording suggests are detected in the cochlear nucleus. The sound signal is band-passed and each signal processed to enhance onsets and offsets. The onset and offset signals are compressed, then clustered both in time and across frequency channels using a network of integrate-and-fire neurons. Onsets and offsets are signalled by spikes, and the timing of these spikes used to segment the sound. 1 Background Traditional speech interpretation techniques based on Fourier transforms, spectrum recoding, and a hidden Markov model or neural network interpretation stage have limitations both in continuous speech and in interpreting speech in the presence of noise, and this has led to interest in front ends modelling biological auditory systems for speech interpretation systems (Ainsworth and Meyer 92; Cosi 93; Cole et al 95). Auditory modelling systems use similar early auditory processing to that used in biological systems. Mammalian auditory processing uses two ears, and the incoming signal is filtered first by the pinna (external ear) and the auditory canal before it causes the tympanic membrane (eardrum) to vibrate. This vibration is then passed on through the bones of the middle ear to the oval window on the cochlea. Inside the cochlea, the pressure wave causes a pattern of vibration to occur on the basilar membrane. This appears to be an active process using both the inner and outer hair cells of the organ of Corti. The movement is detected by the inner hair cells and turned into neural impulses by the neurons of the spiral ganglion. These pass down the auditory nerve, and arrive at various parts of the cochlear nucleus. From there, nerve fibres innervate other areas: the lateral and medial nuclei of the superior olive,</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
