<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SEEMORE: A View-Based Approach to 3-D Object Recognition Using Multiple Visual Cues</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bartlett</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Mel</surname></persName>
							<email>mel@quake.usc.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Biomedical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Southern California Los Angeles</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>90089</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">SEEMORE: A View-Based Approach to 3-D Object Recognition Using Multiple Visual Cues</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A neurally-inspired visual object recognition system is described called SEEMORE, whose goal is to identify common objects from a large known set-independent of 3-D viewiag angle, distance, and non-rigid distortion. SEEMORE&apos;s database consists of 100 objects that are rigid (shovel), non-rigid (telephone cord), articulated (book), statistical (shrubbery), and complex (photographs of scenes). Recognition results were obtained using a set of 102 color and shape feature channels within a simple feedforward network architecture. In response to a test set of 600 novel test views (6 of each object) presented individually in color video images, SEEMORE identified the object correctly 97% of the time (chance is 1%) using a nearest neighbor classifier. Similar levels of performance were obtained for the subset of 15 non-rigid objects. Generalization behavior reveals emergence of striking natural category structure not explicit in the input feature dimensions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
