<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">APPLICATIONS OF ~RROR BACK-PROPAGATION TO PHONETIC CLASSIFICATION</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hong</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Spoken Language Systems Group Laboratory for Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Victor</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Zue</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Spoken Language Systems Group Laboratory for Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">APPLICATIONS OF ~RROR BACK-PROPAGATION TO PHONETIC CLASSIFICATION</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>206</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper is concerced with the use of error back-propagation in phonetic classification. Our objective is to investigate the basic characteristics of back-propagation, and study how the framework of multi-layer perceptrons can be exploited in phonetic recognition. We explore issues such as integration of heterogeneous sources of information, conditioll~ that can affect performance of phonetic classification, internal representations, comparisons with traditional pattern classification techniques, comparisons of different error metrics, and initialization of the network. Our investigation is performed within a set of experiments that attempts to recognize the 16 vowels in American English independent of speaker. Our results are comparable to human performance. Early approaches in phonetic recognition fall into two major extremes: heuristic and algorithmic. Both approaches have their own merits and shortcomings. The heuristic approach has the intuitive appeal that it focuses on the linguistic information in the speech signal and exploits acoustic-phonetic knowledge. HO&apos;fever, the weak control strategy used for utilizing our knowledge has been grossly inadequate. At the other extreme, the algorithmic approach relies primarily on the powerful control strategy offered by well-formulated pattern recognition techniques. However, relatively little is known about how our speech knowledge accumulated over the past few decades can be incorporated into the well-formulated algorithms. We feel that artificial neural networks (ANN) have some characteristics that can potentially enable them to bridge the gap between these two extremes. On the one hand, our speech knowledge can provide guidance to the structure and design of the network. On the other hand, the self-organizing mechanism of ANN can provide a control strategy for utilizing our knowledge. In this paper, we extend our earlier work on the use of artificial neural networks for phonetic recognition [2]. Specifically, we focus our investigation on the following sets of issues. First, we describe the use of the network to integrate heterogeneous sources of information. We will see how classification performance improves as more</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
