<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Clustering data through an analogy to the Potts model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcelo</forename><surname>Blatt</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics of Complex Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Weizmann Institute of Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>76100</postCode>
									<settlement>Rehovot</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shai</forename><surname>Wiseman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics of Complex Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Weizmann Institute of Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>76100</postCode>
									<settlement>Rehovot</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eytan</forename><surname>Domany</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Physics of Complex Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Weizmann Institute of Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>76100</postCode>
									<settlement>Rehovot</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Clustering data through an analogy to the Potts model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A new approach for clustering is proposed. This method is based on an analogy to a physical model; the ferromagnetic Potts model at thermal equilibrium is used as an analog computer for this hard optimization problem. We do not assume any structure of the underlying distribution of the data. Phase space of the Potts model is divided into three regions; ferromagnetic, super-paramagnetic and paramagnetic phases. The region of interest is that corresponding to the super-paramagnetic one, where domains of aligned spins appear. The range of temperatures where these structures are stable is indicated by a non-vanishing magnetic susceptibility. We use a very efficient Monte Carlo algorithm to measure the susceptibility and the spin spin correlation function. The values of the spin spin correlation function, at the super-paramagnetic phase, serve to identify the partition of the data points into clusters. Many natural phenomena can be viewed as optimization processes, and the drive to understand and analyze them yielded powerful mathematical methods. Thus when wishing to solve a hard optimization problem, it may be advantageous to apply these methods through a physical analogy. Indeed, recently techniques from statistical physics have been adapted for solving hard optimization problems (see e.g. Yuille and Kosowsky, 1994). In this work we formulate the problem of clustering in terms of a ferromagnetic Potts spin model. Using the Monte Carlo method we estimate physical quantities such as the spin spin correlation function and the susceptibility, and deduce from them the number of clusters and cluster sizes. Cluster analysis is an important technique in exploratory data analysis and is applied in a variety of engineering and scientific disciplines. The problem of partitionaZ clustering can be formally stated as follows. With everyone of i = 1,2, ... N patterns represented as a point Xi in a d-dimensional metric space, determine the partition of these N points into M groups, called clusters, such that points in a cluster are more similar to each other than to points in different clusters. The value of M also has to be determined.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
