<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Plasticity of Center-Surround Opponent Receptive Fields in Real and Artificial Neural Systems of Vision</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yasui</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Saito</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Electrotechnical Laboratory Tsukuba 305, Japan T. Furukawa Kyushu Institute of Technology lizuka 820</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Kyushu Institute of Technology lizuka 820</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Japan, Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Tsukuba University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Plasticity of Center-Surround Opponent Receptive Fields in Real and Artificial Neural Systems of Vision</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Despite the phylogenic and structural differences, the visual systems of different species, whether vertebrate or invertebrate, share certain functional properties. The center-surround opponent receptive field (CSRF) mechanism represents one such example. Here, analogous CSRFs are shown to be formed in an artificial neural network which learns to localize contours (edges) of the luminance difference. Furthermore, when the input pattern is corrupted by a background noise, the CSRFs of the hidden units becomes shallower and broader with decrease of the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR). The same kind of SNR-dependent plasticity is present in the CSRF of real visual neurons; in bipolar cells of the carp retina as is shown here experimentally, as well as in large monopolar cells of the fly compound eye as was described by others. Also, analogous SNR-dependent plasticity is shown to be present in the biphasic flash responses (BPFR) of these artificial and biological visual systems. Thus, the spatial (CSRF) and temporal (BPFR) filtering properties with which a wide variety of creatures see the world appear to be optimized for detectability of changes in space and time.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
