<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Human Reading and the Curse of Dimensionality</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gale</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
							<email>galem@mcc.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName>TX</roleName><forename type="first">Mcc</forename><surname>Austin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Human Reading and the Curse of Dimensionality</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Whereas optical character recognition (OCR) systems learn to classify single characters; people learn to classify long character strings in parallel, within a single fixation. This difference is surprising because high dimensionality is associated with poor classification learning. This paper suggests that the human reading system avoids these problems because the number of to-be-classified images is reduced by consistent and optimal eye fixation positions, and by character sequence regularities. An interesting difference exists between human reading and optical character recognition (OCR) systems. The input/output dimensionality of character classification in human reading is much greater than that for OCR systems (see Figure 1). OCR systems classify one character at time; while the human reading system classifies as many as 8-13 characters per eye fixation (Rayner, 1979) and within a fixation, character category and sequence information is extracted in parallel (Blanchard, McConkie, Zola, and Wolverton, 1984; Reicher, 1969). OCR (Low Dbnensionality)</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
