<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">DYNAMICS OF ANALOG NEURAL NETWORKS WITH TIME DELAY</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Division of Applied Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge Massachusetts</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Westervelt</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Division of Applied Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge Massachusetts</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">DYNAMICS OF ANALOG NEURAL NETWORKS WITH TIME DELAY</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>568</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A time delay in the response of the neurons in a network can induce sustained oscillation and chaos. We present a stability criterion based on local stability analysis to prevent sustained oscillation in symmetric delay networks, and show an example of chaotic dynamics in a non-symmetric delay network. L INTRODUCTION Understanding how time delay affects the dynamics of neural networks is important for two reasons: First, some degree of time delay is intrinsic to any physically realized network, both in biological neural systems and in electronic artificial neural networks. As we will show, it is not obvious what constitutes a &quot;small&quot; (i.e. ignorable) delay which will not qualitatively change the network dynamics. For some network configurations, delay much smaller than the intrinsic relaxation time of the network can induce collective oscillatory behavior not predicted by mathematical models which ignore delay. These oscillations mayor may not be desirable; in either case, one should understand when and how new dynamics can appear. The second reason to study time delay is for its intentional use in parallel computation. The dynamics of neural networks which always converge to fixed points are now fairly well understood. Several neural network models have appeared recently which use time delay to produce dynamic computation such as associative recall of sequences [Kleinfeld,1986; Sompolinsky and Kanter, 1986]. It has also been suggested that time delay produces an effective noise in the network dynamics which can yield improved recall of memories [Conwell, 1987] Finally, to the extent that neural networks research is inspired by biological systems, the known presence of time delays in a many real neural systems suggests their usefulness in parallel computation. In this paper we will show how time delay in an analog neural network can produce sustained oscillation and chaos. In section 2 we consider the case of a symmetrically connected network. It is known [Cohen and Grossberg, 1983; Hopfield, 1984] that in the absence of time delay a symmetric network will always converge to a fixed point attractor. We show that adding a fixed delay to the response of each neuron will produce sustained oscillation when the magnitude of the delay exceeds a critical value, which depends on the neuron gain and the network connection topology. We then analyze the</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
