<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:12+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">CRICKET WIND DETECTION</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Neurobiology Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
									<country key="US">U.S.A</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">CRICKET WIND DETECTION</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>802</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A great deal of interest has recently been focused on theories concerning parallel distributed processing in central nervous systems. In particular, many researchers have become very interested in the structure and function of &quot;computational maps&quot; in sensory systems. As defined in a recent review (Knudsen et al, 1987), a &quot;map&quot; is an array of nerve cells, within which there is a systematic variation in the &quot;tuning&quot; of neighboring cells for a particular parameter. For example, the projection from retina to visual cortex is a relatively simple topographic map; each cortical hypercolumn itself contains a more complex &quot;computational&quot; map of preferred line orientation representing the angle of tilt of a simple line stimulus. The overall goal of the research in my lab is to determine how a relatively complex mapped sensory system extracts and encodes information from external stimuli. The preparation we study is the cercal sensory system of the cricket, Acheta domesticus. Crickets (and many other insects) have two antenna-like appendages at the rear of their abdomen, covered with hundreds of &quot;filiform&quot; hairs, resembling bristles on a bottle brush. Deflection of these filiform hairs by wind currents activates mechanosensory receptors, which project into the terminal abdominal ganglion to form a topographic representation (or &quot;map&quot;) of &quot;wind space&quot;. Primary sensory interneurons having</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
