<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement Learning for Dynamic C· hannel Allocation in Cellular Telephone Systems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satinder</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Lab. for Info. and Decision Sciences MIT Cambridge</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309-0430, 02139</postCode>
									<region>CO, MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dimitri</forename><surname>Bertsekas</surname></persName>
							<email>bertsekas@lids.mit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Lab. for Info. and Decision Sciences MIT Cambridge</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309-0430, 02139</postCode>
									<region>CO, MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Reinforcement Learning for Dynamic C· hannel Allocation in Cellular Telephone Systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In cellular telephone systems, an important problem is to dynamically allocate the communication resource (channels) so as to maximize service in a stochastic caller environment. This problem is naturally formulated as a dynamic programming problem and we use a reinforcement learning (RL) method to find dynamic channel allocation policies that are better than previous heuristic solutions. The policies obtained perform well for a broad variety of call traffic patterns. We present results on a large cellular system with approximately 49 49 states. In cellular communication systems, an important problem is to allocate the communication resource (bandwidth) so as to maximize the service provided to a set of mobile callers whose demand for service changes stochastically. A given geographical area is divided into mutually disjoint cells, and each cell serves the calls that are within its boundaries (see Figure 1a). The total system bandwidth is divided into channels, with each channel centered around a frequency. Each channel can be used simultaneously at different cells, provided these cells are sufficiently separated spatially, so that there is no interference between them. The minimum separation distance between simultaneous reuse of the same channel is called the channel reuse constraint. When a call requests service in a given cell either a free channel (one that does not violate the channel reuse constraint) may be assigned to the call, or else the call is blocked from the system; this will happen if no free channel can be found. Also, when a mobile caller crosses from one cell to another, the call is &quot;handed off&quot; to the cell of entry; that is, a new free channel is provided to the call at the new cell. If no such channel is available, the call must be dropped/disconnected from the system.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
