<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Model of Recurrent Interactions in Primary Visual Cortex</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eldanuel</forename><surname>Todorov</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Brain and Cognitive Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">MIT</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E25-526, 02139</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Athanassios</forename><surname>Siapas</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Brain and Cognitive Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">MIT</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E25-526, 02139</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Solders</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Brain and Cognitive Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">MIT</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>E25-526, 02139</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Model of Recurrent Interactions in Primary Visual Cortex</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A general feature of the cerebral cortex is its massive intercon-nectivity-it has been estimated anatomically [19] that cortical neurons receive upwards of 5,000 synapses, the majority of which originate from other nearby cortical neurons. Numerous experiments in primary visual cortex (VI) have revealed strongly nonlin-ear interactions between stimulus elements which activate classical and non-classical receptive field regions. Recurrent cortical connections likely contribute substantially to these effects. However, most theories of visual processing have either assumed a feedfor-ward processing scheme [7], or have used recurrent interactions to account for isolated effects only [1, 16, 18]. Since nonlinear systems cannot in general be taken apart and analyzed in pieces, it is not clear what one learns by building a recurrent model that only accounts for one, or very few phenomena. Here we develop a relatively simple model of recurrent interactions in VI, that reflects major anatomical and physiological features of intracortical connectivity, and simultaneously accounts for a wide range of phenomena observed physiologically. All phenomena we address are strongly nonlinear, and cannot be explained by linear feedforward models. 1 The Model We analyze the mean firing rates observed in oriented VI cells in response to stimuli consisting of an inner circular grating and all outer annular grating. Mean responses of individual cells are modeled by single-valued &quot;cellular&quot; response functions, whose arguments are the mean firing rates of the cell&apos;s inputs and their maximal synaptic conductances.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
