<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Multi-Grid Methods for Reinforcement Learning in Controlled Diffusion Processes</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephan</forename><surname>Pareigis</surname></persName>
							<email>stp@numerik.uni-kiel.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Lehrstuhl Praktische Mathematik Christian-Albrechts-U niversi tat Kiel Kiel</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Multi-Grid Methods for Reinforcement Learning in Controlled Diffusion Processes</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Reinforcement learning methods for discrete and semi-Markov decision problems such as Real-Time Dynamic Programming can be generalized for Controlled Diffusion Processes. The optimal control problem reduces to a boundary value problem for a fully nonlinear second-order elliptic differential equation of Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman (HJB-) type. Numerical analysis provides multi-grid methods for this kind of equation. In the case of Learning Control , however, the systems of equations on the various grid-levels are obtained using observed information (transitions and local cost). To ensure consistency, special attention needs to be directed toward the type of time and space discretization during the observation. An algorithm for multi-grid observation is proposed. The multi-grid algorithm is demonstrated on a simple queuing problem.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
