<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">TEMPORAL PATTERNS OF ACTIVITY IN NEURAL NETWORKS</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1988-01-05">January 5, 1988</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paolo</forename><surname>Gaudiano</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Aerospace Engineering Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309</postCode>
									<settlement>Boulder</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">TEMPORAL PATTERNS OF ACTIVITY IN NEURAL NETWORKS</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1988-01-05">January 5, 1988</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Patterns of activity over real neural structures are known to exhibit time-dependent behavior. It would seem that the brain may be capable of utilizing temporal behavior of activity in neural networks as a way of performing functions which cannot otherwise be easily implemented. These might include the origination of sequential behavior and the recognition of time-dependent stimuli. A model is presented here which uses neuronal populations with recurrent feedback connections in an attempt to observe and describe the resulting time-dependent behavior. Shortcomings and problems inherent to this model are discussed. Current models by other researchers are reviewed and their similarities and differences discussed. METHODS / PRELIMINARY RESULTS 297 In previous papers,[2,3] computer models were presented that simulate a net consisting of two spatially organized populations of realistic neurons. The populations are richly interconnected and are shown to exhibit internally sustained activity. It was shown that if the neurons have response times significantly shorter than the typical unit time characteristic of the input patterns (usually 1 msec), the populations will exhibit time-dependent behavior. This will typically result in the net falling into a limit cycle. By a limit cycle, it is meant that the population falls into activity patterns during which all of the active cells fire in a cyclic, periodic fashion. Although the period of firing of the individual cells may be different, after a fixed time the overall population activity will repeat in a cyclic, periodic fashion. For populations organized in 7x7 grids, the limit cycle will usually start 20~200 msec after the input is turned off, and its period will be in the order of 20-100 msec. The point ofinterest is that ifthe net is allowed to undergo synaptic modifications by means of a modified hebbian learning rule while being presented with a specific spatial pattern (i.e., cells at specific spatial locations within the net are externally stimulated), subsequent presentations of the same pattern with different temporal characteristics will cause the population to recall patterns which are spatially identical (the same cells will be active) but which have different temporal qualities. In other words, the net can fall into a different limit cycle. These limit cycles seem to behave as attractors in that similar input patterns will result in the same limit cycle, and hence each distinct limit cycle appears to have a basin of attraction. Hence a net which can only learn a small</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
