<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Size of multilayer networks for exact learning: analytic approach</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andre</forename><surname>Elisseefl&amp;apos;</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">D~pt Mathematiques et Informatique</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">LIP, URA 1398 CNRS Ecole Normale Superieure de Lyon 46 allee d&apos;Italie F69364 Lyon cedex 07</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ecole Normale</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Superieure de Lyon 46 allee d&apos;Italie F69364 Lyon cedex 07</settlement>
									<country>FRANCE, FRANCE</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Helene</forename><surname>Paugam-Moisy</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">D~pt Mathematiques et Informatique</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">LIP, URA 1398 CNRS Ecole Normale Superieure de Lyon 46 allee d&apos;Italie F69364 Lyon cedex 07</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ecole Normale</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Superieure de Lyon 46 allee d&apos;Italie F69364 Lyon cedex 07</settlement>
									<country>FRANCE, FRANCE</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Size of multilayer networks for exact learning: analytic approach</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This article presents a new result about the size of a multilayer neural network computing real outputs for exact learning of a finite set of real samples. The architecture of the network is feedforward, with one hidden layer and several outputs. Starting from a fixed training set, we consider the network as a function of its weights. We derive, for a wide family of transfer functions, a lower and an upper bound on the number of hidden units for exact learning, given the size of the dataset and the dimensions of the input and output spaces. 1 RELATED WORKS The context of our work is rather similar to the well-known results of Baum et al. [1, 2,3,5, 10], but we consider both real inputs and outputs, instead ofthe dichotomies usually addressed. We are interested in learning exactly all the examples of a fixed database, hence our work is different from stating that multilayer networks are universal approximators [6, 8, 9]. Since we consider real outputs and not only dichotomies, it is not straightforward to compare our results to the recent works about the VC-dimension of multilayer networks [11, 12, 13]. Our study is more closely related to several works of Sontag [14, 15], but with different hypotheses on the transfer functions of the units. Finally, our approach is based on geometrical considerations and is close to the model of Coetzee and Stonick [4]. First we define the model of network and the notations and second we develop our analytic approach and prove the fundamental theorem. In the last section, we discuss our point of view and propose some practical consequences of the result.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
