<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">MODELING SMALL OSCILLATING BIOLOGICAL NETWORKS IN ANALOG VLSI</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sylvie</forename><surname>Ryckebusch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">California Instit ute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91125</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bower</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">California Instit ute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91125</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Carver</forename><surname>Mead</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">California Instit ute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91125</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">MODELING SMALL OSCILLATING BIOLOGICAL NETWORKS IN ANALOG VLSI</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>384</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We have used analog VLSI technology to model a class of small oscillating biological neural circuits known as central pattern generators (CPG). These circuits generate rhythmic patterns of activity which drive locomotor behaviour in the animal. We have designed, fabricated, and tested a model neuron circuit which relies on many of the same mechanisms as a biological central pattern generator neuron, such as delays and internal feedback. We show that this neuron can be used to build several small circuits based on known biological CPG circuits, and that these circuits produce patterns of output which are very similar to the observed biological patterns. To date, researchers in applied neural networks have tended to focus on mam-malian systems as the primary source of potentially useful biological information. However, invertebrate systems may represent a source of ideas in many ways more appropriate, given current levels of engineering sophistication in building neural-like systems, and given the state of biological understanding of mammalian circuits. Invertebrate systems are based on orders of magnitude smaller numbers of neurons than are mammalian systems. The networks we will consider here, for example, are composed of about a dozen neurons, which is well within the demonstrated capabilities of current hardware fabrication techniques. Furthermore, since much more detailed structural information is available about these systems than for most systems in higher animals, insights can be guided by real information rather than by guesswork. Finally, even though they are constructed of small numbers of neurons, these networks have numerous interesting and potentially even useful properties. CENTRAL PATTERN GENERATORS Of all the invertebrate neural networks currently being investigated by neurobi-ologists, the class of networks known as central pattern generators (CPGs) may be especially worthy of attention. A CPG is responsible for generating oscillatory neural activity that governs specific patterns of motor output, and can generate its pattern of activity when isolated from its normal neuronal inputs. This prop</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
