<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Compositionality, MDL Priors, and Object Recognition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Elie</forename><surname>Bienenstock</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02912</postCode>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Geman</surname></persName>
							<email>(geman@dam.brown.edu)</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02912</postCode>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Potter</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Brown University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02912</postCode>
									<settlement>Providence</settlement>
									<region>RI</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Compositionality, MDL Priors, and Object Recognition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Division of Applied Mathematics,</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Images are ambiguous at each of many levels of a contextual hierarchy. Nevertheless, the high-level interpretation of most scenes is unambiguous, as evidenced by the superior performance of humans. This observation argues for global vision models, such as de-formable templates. Unfortunately, such models are computation-ally intractable for unconstrained problems. We propose a composi-tional model in which primitives are recursively composed, subject to syntactic restrictions, to form tree-structured objects and object groupings. Ambiguity is propagated up the hierarchy in the form of multiple interpretations, which are later resolved by a Bayesian, equivalently minimum-description-Iength, cost functional. 1 Bayesian decision theory and compositionaiity In his Essay on Probability, Laplace (1812) devotes a short chapter-his &quot;Sixth Principle&quot;-to what we call today the Bayesian decision rule. Laplace observes that we interpret a &quot;regular combination,&quot; e.g., an arrangement of objects that displays some particular symmetry, as having resulted from a &quot;regular cause&quot; rather than arisen by chance. It is not, he argues, that a symmetric configuration is less likely to happen by chance than another arrangement. Rather, it is that among all possible combinations, which are equally favored by chance, there are very few of the regular type: &quot;On a table we see letters arranged in this order, Constantinople, and we judge that this arrangement is not the result of chance, not because it is less possible than the others, for if this word were not employed in any language</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
