<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Multi-time Models for Temporally Abstract Planning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Dayan &amp; Hinton</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Dayan &amp; Hinton</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="1977">1977. 1986. 1985. 1993. 1993</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Doina</forename><surname>Precup</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Massachusetts Amherst</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>01003</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Sutton</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Massachusetts Amherst</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>01003</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Multi-time Models for Temporally Abstract Planning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Dayan &amp; Hinton</publisher>
							<date type="published" when="1977">1977. 1986. 1985. 1993. 1993</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Planning and learning at multiple levels of temporal abstraction is a key problem for artificial intelligence. In this paper we summarize an approach to this problem based on the mathematical framework of Markov decision processes and reinforcement learning. Current model-based reinforcement learning is based on one-step models that cannot represent common-sense higher-level actions, such as going to lunch, grasping an object, or flying to Denver. This paper generalizes prior work on temporally abstract models [Sutton, 1995] and extends it from the prediction setting to include actions, control, and planning. We introduce a more general form of temporally abstract model, the multi-time model, and establish its suitability for planning and learning by virtue of its relationship to the Bellman equations. This paper summarizes the theoretical framework of multi-time models and illustrates their potential advantages in a grid world planning task. The need for hierarchical and abstract planning is a fundamental problem in AI (see, e.g.,. Model-based reinforcement learning offers a possible solution to the problem of integrating planning with real-time learning and decision-making (Peng &amp; Williams, 1993, Moore &amp; Atkeson, 1993; Sutton and Barto, 1998). However, current model-based reinforcement learning is based on one-step models that cannot represent common-sense, higher-level actions. Modeling such actions requires the ability to handle different, interrelated levels of temporal abstraction. A new approach to modeling at multiple time scales was introduced by Sutton (1995) based on prior work by Singh, Dayan, and Sutton and Pinette. This approach enables models of the environment at different temporal scales to be intermixed, producing temporally abstract models. However, that work was concerned only with predicting the environment. This paper summarizes an extension of the approach including actions and control of the environment [Precup &amp; Sutton, 1997]. In particular, we generalize the usual notion of a</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
