<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">MELONET I: Neural Nets for Inventing Baroque-Style Chorale Variations</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Hornel</surname></persName>
							<email>dominik@ira.uka.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institut fur Logik</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Komplexitat und Deduktionssysteme Universitat Fridericiana Karlsruhe (TH)</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Am Fasanengarten 5</addrLine>
									<postCode>D-76128</postCode>
									<settlement>Karlsruhe</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">MELONET I: Neural Nets for Inventing Baroque-Style Chorale Variations</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>MELONET I is a multi-scale neural network system producing baroque-style melodic variations. Given a melody, the system invents a four-part chorale harmonization and a variation of any chorale voice, after being trained on music pieces of composers like J. S. Bach and J. Pachelbel. Unlike earlier approaches to the learning of melodic structure, the system is able to learn and reproduce high-order structure like harmonic, motif and phrase structure in melodic sequences. This is achieved by using mutually interacting feedforward networks operating at different time scales, in combination with Kohonen networks to classify and recognize musical structure. The results are chorale partitas in the style of J. Pachel-bel. Their quality has been judged by experts to be comparable to improvisations invented by an experienced human organist.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
