<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Selecting weighting factors in logarithmic opinion pools</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Heskes</surname></persName>
							<email>tom@mbfys.kun.nl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Foundation for Neural Networks</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nijmegen Geert Grooteplein 21</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>6525 EZ</postCode>
									<settlement>Nijmegen</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Selecting weighting factors in logarithmic opinion pools</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A simple linear averaging of the outputs of several networks as e.g. in bagging [3], seems to follow naturally from a bias/variance decomposition of the sum-squared error. The sum-squared error of the average model is a quadratic function of the weighting factors assigned to the networks in the ensemble [7], suggesting a quadratic programming algorithm for finding the &quot;optimal&quot; weighting factors. If we interpret the output of a network as a probability statement, the sum-squared error corresponds to minus the loglikelihood or the Kullback-Leibler divergence, and linear averaging of the outputs to logarithmic averaging of the probability statements: the logarithmic opinion pool. The crux of this paper is that this whole story about model averaging , bias/variance decompositions, and quadratic programming to find the optimal weighting factors, is not specific for the sum-squared error, but applies to the combination of probability statements of any kind in a logarithmic opinion pool, as long as the Kullback-Leibler divergence plays the role of the error measure. As examples we treat model averaging for classification models under a cross-entropy error measure and models for estimating variances.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
