<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:13+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Graph Matching with Hierarchical Discrete Relaxation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of York York</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>YOl 5DD</postCode>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Edwin</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Hancock</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of York York</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>YOl 5DD</postCode>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Graph Matching with Hierarchical Discrete Relaxation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Our aim in this paper is to develop a Bayesian framework for matching hierarchical relational models. The goal is to make discrete label assignments so as to optimise a global cost function that draws information concerning the consistency of match from different levels of the hierarchy. Our Bayesian development naturally distinguishes between intra-level and inter-level constraints. This allows the impact of reassigning a match to be assessed not only at its own (or peer) level ofrepresentation, but also upon its parents and children in the hierarchy. 1 Introd uction Hierarchical graphical structures are of critical importance in the interpretation of sensory or perceptual data. For instance, following the influential work of Marr [6] there has been sustained efforts at effectively organising and processing hierarchical information in vision systems. There are a plethora of concrete examples which include pyramidal hierarchies [3] that are concerned with multi-resolution information processing and conceptual hierarchies [4] which are concerned with processing at different levels of abstraction. Key to the development of techniques for hierarchical information processing is the desire to exploit not only the intra-level constraints applying at the individual levels of representation but also inter-level constraints operating between different levels of the hierarchy. If used effectively these inter-level constraints can be brought to bear on the interpretation of uncertain image entities in such a way as to improve the fidelity of interpretation achieved by single level means. Viewed as an additional information source, inter-level constraints can be used to resolve ambiguities that would persist if single-level constraints alone were used.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
