<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Convergence Rates of Algorithms for Visual Search: Detecting Visual Contours</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Yuille</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Smith-Kettlewell Inst . San Francisco</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94115</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Convergence Rates of Algorithms for Visual Search: Detecting Visual Contours</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>James M. Coughlan Smith-Kettlewell Inst. San Francisco, CA 94115 This paper formulates the problem of visual search as Bayesian inference and defines a Bayesian ensemble of problem instances. In particular, we address the problem of the detection of visual contours in noise/clutter by optimizing a global criterion which combines local intensity and geometry information. We analyze the convergence rates of A * search algorithms using results from information theory to bound the probability of rare events within the Bayesian ensemble. This analysis determines characteristics of the domain , which we call order parameters, that determine the convergence rates. In particular, we present a specific admissible A * algorithm with pruning which converges, with high probability, with expected time O(N) in the size of the problem. In addition , we briefly summarize extensions of this work which address fundamental limits of target contour detectability (Le. algorithm independent results) and the use of non-admissible heuristics.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
