<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Finite-Sample Convergence Rates for Q-Learning and Indirect Algorithms</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Kearns</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">AT&amp;T Labs</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>180 Park Avenue Florham Park</addrLine>
									<postCode>07932</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Satinder</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">AT&amp;T Labs</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>180 Park Avenue Florham Park</addrLine>
									<postCode>07932</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Finite-Sample Convergence Rates for Q-Learning and Indirect Algorithms</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper, we address two issues of long-standing interest in the reinforcement learning literature. First, what kinds of performance guarantees can be made for Q-learning after only a finite number of actions? Second, what quantitative comparisons can be made between Q-learning and model-based (indirect) approaches, which use experience to estimate next-state distributions for off-line value iteration? We first show that both Q-learning and the indirect approach enjoy rather rapid convergence to the optimal policy as a function of the number of state transitions observed. In particular, on the order of only (Nlog(1/c)/c 2)(log(N) + loglog(l/c)) transitions are sufficient for both algorithms to come within c of the optimal policy, in an idealized model that assumes the observed transitions are &quot;well-mixed&quot; throughout an N-state MDP. Thus, the two approaches have roughly the same sample complexity. Perhaps surprisingly, this sample complexity is far less than what is required for the model-based approach to actually construct a good approximation to the next-state distribution. The result also shows that the amount of memory required by the model-based approach is closer to N than to N 2 • For either approach, to remove the assumption that the observed transitions are well-mixed, we consider a model in which the transitions are determined by a fixed, arbitrary exploration policy. Bounds on the number of transitions required in order to achieve a desired level of performance are then related to the stationary distribution and mixing time of this policy.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
