<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Surround Suppression in VI Neurons with a Statistically-Derived Normalization Model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eero</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Simoncelli</surname></persName>
							<email>eero.simoncelli@nyu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for Neural Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Center for Neural Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Abstract</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences New York University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">New York University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Odelia</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
							<email>odelia@cns.nyu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for Neural Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Center for Neural Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Abstract</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences New York University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">New York University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Modeling Surround Suppression in VI Neurons with a Statistically-Derived Normalization Model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We examine the statistics of natural monochromatic images decomposed using a multi-scale wavelet basis. Although the coefficients of this representation are nearly decorrelated, they exhibit important higher-order statistical dependencies that cannot be eliminated with purely linear pro-c~ssing. In particular, rectified coefficients corresponding to basis functions at neighboring spatial positions, orientations and scales are highly correlated. A method of removing these dependencies is to divide each coefficient by a weighted combination of its rectified neighbors. Several successful models of the steady-state behavior of neurons in primary visual cortex are based on such &quot;divisive normalization&quot; computations, and thus our analysis provides a theoretical justification for these models. Perhaps more importantly, the statistical measurements explicitly specify the weights that should be used in computing the normalization signal. We demonstrate that this weighting is qualitatively consistent with recent physiological experiments that characterize the suppressive effect of stimuli presented outside of the classical receptive field. Our observations thus provide evidence for the hypothesis that early visual neural processing is well matched to these statistical properties of images. An appealing hypothesis for neural processing states that sensory systems develop in response to the statistical properties of the signals to which they are exposed [e.g., 1, 2]. This has led many researchers to look for a means of deriving a model of cortical processing purely from a statistical characterization of sensory signals. In particular, many such attempts are based on the notion that neural responses should be statistically independent. The pixels of digitized natural images are highly redundant, but one can always find a linear decomposition (i.e., principal component analysis) that eliminates second-order cor</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
