<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Blind Separation of Filtered Sources Using State-Space Approach</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liqing</forename><surname>Zhang·</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory for Open Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brain Science Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">RIKEN Saitama</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Wako shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>351-0198</postCode>
									<country key="JP">JAPAN</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrzej</forename><surname>Cichocki</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory for Open Information Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Brain Science Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">RIKEN Saitama</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Wako shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>351-0198</postCode>
									<country key="JP">JAPAN</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Blind Separation of Filtered Sources Using State-Space Approach</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper we present a novel approach to multichannel blind separation/generalized deconvolution, assuming that both mixing and demixing models are described by stable linear state-space systems. We decompose the blind separation problem into two process: separation and state estimation. Based on the minimization of Kullback-Leibler Divergence, we develop a novel learning algorithm to train the matrices in the output equation. To estimate the state of the demixing model, we introduce a new concept, called hidden innovation, to numerically implement the Kalman filter. Computer simulations are given to show the validity and high effectiveness of the state-space approach. 1 Introd uction The field of blind separation and deconvolution has grown dramatically during recent years due to its similarity to the separation feature in human brain, as well as its rapidly growing applications in various fields, such as telecommunication systems, image enhancement and biomedical signal processing. The blind source separation problem is to recover independent sources from sensor outputs without assuming any priori knowledge of the original signals besides certain statistic features. Refer to review papers [lJ and [5J for the current state of theory and methods in the field. Although there exist a number of models and methods, such as the infomax, natural gradient approach and equivariant adaptive algorithms, for separating blindly independent sources, there still are several challenges in generalizing mixture to dy-·On leave from South China University of Technology, China tan leave from Warsaw University of Technology, Poland</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
