<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Information Maximization in Single Neurons</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Stemmler</surname></persName>
							<email>Email: stemmler@klab.caltech.edu.koch@klab.caltech.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computation and Neural Systems Program Caltech</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>139-74, 91 125</postCode>
									<settlement>Pasadena</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computation and Neural Systems Program Caltech</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>139-74, 91 125</postCode>
									<settlement>Pasadena</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Information Maximization in Single Neurons</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Information from the senses must be compressed into the limited range of firing rates generated by spiking nerve cells. Optimal compression uses all firing rates equally often, implying that the nerve cell&apos;s response matches the statistics of naturally occurring stimuli. Since changing the voltage-dependent ionic conductances in the cell membrane alters the flow of information, an unsupervised, non-Hebbian, developmental learning rule is derived to adapt the conductances in Hodgkin-Huxley model neurons. By maximizing the rate of information transmission, each firing rate within the model neuron&apos;s limited dynamic range is used equally often. An efficient neuronal representation of incoming sensory information should take advantage of the regularity and scale invariance of stimulus features in the natural world. In the case of vision, this regularity is reflected in the typical probabilities of encountering particular visual contrasts, spatial orientations, or colors [1]. Given these probabilities, an optimized neural code would eliminate any redundancy, while devoting increased representation to commonly encountered features. At the level of a single spiking neuron, information about a potentially large range of stimuli is compressed into a finite range of firing rates, since the maximum firing rate of a neuron is limited. Optimizing the information transmission through a single neuron in the presence of uniform, additive noise has an intuitive interpretation: the most efficient representation of the input uses every firing rate with equal probability. An analogous principle for non-spiking neurons has been tested experimentally by Laughlin [2], who matched the statistics</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
