<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Non-linear PI Control Inspired by Biological Control Systems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lyndon</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
							<email>·Jyndon.j .brown@usa.dupont.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Experimental Station</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">E.!. DuPont deNemours &amp; Co. Wilmington</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19880</postCode>
									<region>DE</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gonye</surname></persName>
							<email>Gregory.E.Gonye-PHD@usa.dupont.com James.S.Scwhaber@usa.dupont.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Experimental Station</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">E.!. DuPont deNemours &amp; Co. Wilmington</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19880</postCode>
									<region>DE</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Schwaber</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Experimental Station</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">E.!. DuPont deNemours &amp; Co. Wilmington</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19880</postCode>
									<region>DE</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Non-linear PI Control Inspired by Biological Control Systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Address correspondence to this author</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A non-linear modification to PI control is motivated by a model of a signal transduction pathway active in mammalian blood pressure regulation. This control algorithm, labeled PII (proportional with intermittent integral), is appropriate for plants requiring exact set-point matching and disturbance attenuation in the presence of infrequent step changes in load disturbances or set-point. The proportional aspect of the controller is independently designed to be a disturbance attenuator and set-point matching is achieved by intermittently invoking an integral controller. The mechanisms observed in the Angiotensin 11/ AT1 signaling pathway are used to control the switching of the integral control. Improved performance over PI control is shown on a model of cyc1opentenol production. A sign change in plant gain at the desirable operating point causes traditional PI control to result in an unstable system. Application of this new approach to this problem results in stable exact set-point matching for achievable set-points. Biological processes have evolved sophisticated mechanisms for solving difficult control problems. By analyzing and understanding these natural systems it is possible that principles can be derived which are applicable to general control systems. This approach has already been the basis for the field of artificial neural networks, which are loosely based on a model of the electrical signaling of neurons. A suitable candidate system for analysis is blood pressure control. Tight control of blood pressure is critical for survival of an animal. Chronically high levels can lead to premature death. Low blood pressure can lead to oxygen and nutrient deprivation and sudden load changes must be quickly responded to or loss of consciousness can result. The baroreflex, reflexive change of heart rate in response to blood pressure challenge, has been previously studied in order to develop some insights into biological control systems [1, 2, 3].</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
