<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Role of Lateral Cortical Competition in Ocular Dominance Development</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Piepenbrock</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University of Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>FR 2-1; Franklinstr. 28-29, 10587 Berlin</addrLine>
									<country>Germany&apos;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Obermayer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technical University of Berlin</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>FR 2-1; Franklinstr. 28-29, 10587 Berlin</addrLine>
									<country>Germany&apos;</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Role of Lateral Cortical Competition in Ocular Dominance Development</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Lateral competition within a layer of neurons sharpens and localizes the response to an input stimulus. Here, we investigate a model for the activity dependent development of ocular dominance maps which allows to vary the degree of lateral competition. For weak competition, it resembles a correlation-based learning model and for strong competition, it becomes a self-organizing map. Thus, in the regime of weak competition the receptive fields are shaped by the second order statistics of the input patterns, whereas in the regime of strong competition, the higher moments and &quot;features&quot; of the individual patterns become important. When correlated localized stimuli from two eyes drive the cortical development we find (i) that a topographic map and binocular, localized receptive fields emerge when the degree of competition exceeds a critical value and (ii) that receptive fields exhibit eye dominance beyond a second critical value. For anti-correlated activity between the eyes, the second order statistics drive the system to develop ocular dominance even for weak competition, but no topography emerges. Topography is established only beyond a critical degree of competition.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
