<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">NEURAL APPROACH FOR TV IMAGE COMPRESSION USING A HOPFIELD TYPE NETWORK</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martine</forename><surname>Naillon</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire d&apos;Electronique et de Physique Appliquee</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3 Avenue DESCARTES</addrLine>
									<postBox>BP 15</postBox>
									<postCode>94451</postCode>
									<settlement>LIMEIL BREVANNES Cedex</settlement>
									<country key="FR">FRANCE</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jean-Bernard</forename><surname>Theeten</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratoire d&apos;Electronique et de Physique Appliquee</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>3 Avenue DESCARTES</addrLine>
									<postBox>BP 15</postBox>
									<postCode>94451</postCode>
									<settlement>LIMEIL BREVANNES Cedex</settlement>
									<country key="FR">FRANCE</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">NEURAL APPROACH FOR TV IMAGE COMPRESSION USING A HOPFIELD TYPE NETWORK</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>264 * LEP : A member of the Philips Research Organization.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A self-organizing Hopfield network has been developed in the context of Vector Ouantiza-tion, aiming at compression of television images. The metastable states of the spin glass-like network are used as an extra storage resource using the Minimal Overlap learning rule (Krauth and Mezard 1987) to optimize the organization of the attractors. The sel f-organi zi ng scheme that we have devised results in the generation of an adaptive codebook for any qiven TV image. I NTRODOCTI ON The ability of an Hopfield network (Little,1974; Hopfield, 1982,1986; Amit. and al., 1987; Personnaz and al. 1985; Hertz, 1988) to behave as an associative memory usua 11 y aSSlJ11es a pri ori knowl edge of the patterns to be stored. As in many applications they are unknown, the aim of this work is to develop a network capable to learn how to select its attractors. TV image compression using Vector Quantization (V.Q.)(Gray, 1984), a key issue for HOTV transmission, is a typical case, since the non neural algorithms which generate the list of codes (the codebookl are suboptimal. As an alternative to the prani si ng neural canpressi on techni ques (Jackel et al., 1987; Kohonen, 1988; Grossberg, 1987; Cottrel et al., 19B7) our idea is to use the metastability in a spin glass-like net as an additional storage resource and to derive after a &quot;cl assi cal II cl usteri nq a 1 gori thm a sel f-organi zi ng sheme for generatf ng adaptively the codebook. We present the illustrative case of 2D-vectors.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
