<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Synergy and redundancy among brain cells of behaving monkeys</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Itay</forename><surname>Gat·</surname></persName>
							<email>tishby}@cs.huji.ac.il</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Institute of Computer Science and Center for Neural Computation</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Computer Science and Center for Neural Computa-tion</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Hebrew University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91904</postCode>
									<settlement>Jerusalem</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">The Hebrew University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91904</postCode>
									<settlement>Jerusalem</settlement>
									<country key="IL">Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Synergy and redundancy among brain cells of behaving monkeys</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Permanent address: 112 I. Gat and N. Tishby</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Naftali Tishby t NEC Research Institute 4 Independence Way Princeton N J 08540 Determining the relationship between the activity of a single nerve cell to that of an entire population is a fundamental question that bears on the basic neural computation paradigms. In this paper we apply an information theoretic approach to quantify the level of cooperative activity among cells in a behavioral context. It is possible to discriminate between synergetic activity of the cells vs. redundant activity, depending on the difference between the information they provide when measured jointly and the information they provide independently. We define a synergy value that is positive in the first case and negative in the second and show that the synergy value can be measured by detecting the behavioral mode of the animal from simultaneously recorded activity of the cells. We observe that among cortical cells positive synergy can be found, while cells from the basal ganglia , active during the same task, do not exhibit similar synergetic activity. titay,</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
