<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Spectral Cues in Human Sound Localization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Craig</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Jin</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Carlile</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Corderoy</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andre</forename><surname>Van Schaik</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Physiology and Department of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physiology and Institute of Biomedical Research Univ. of Sydney</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Physiology Univ. of Sydney</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep4">Department of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Univ. of Sydney</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2006, 2006, 2006</postCode>
									<region>NSW, NSW, NSW</region>
									<country>Australia, Australia, Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Univ. of Sydney</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>2006</postCode>
									<region>NSW</region>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Spectral Cues in Human Sound Localization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The differential contribution of the monaural and interaural spectral cues to human sound localization was examined using a combined psy-chophysical and analytical approach. The cues to a sound&apos;s location were correlated on an individual basis with the human localization responses to a variety of spectrally manipulated sounds. The spectral cues derive from the acoustical filtering of an individual&apos;s auditory periphery which is characterized by the measured head-related transfer functions (HRTFs). Auditory localization performance was determined in virtual auditory space (VAS). Psychoacoustical experiments were conducted in which the amplitude spectra of the sound stimulus was varied indepen-dentlyat each ear while preserving the normal timing cues, an impossibility in the free-field environment. Virtual auditory noise stimuli were generated over earphones for a specified target direction such that there was a &quot;false&quot; flat spectrum at the left eardrum. Using the subject&apos;s HRTFs, the sound spectrum at the right eardrum was then adjusted so that either the true right monaural spectral cue or the true interaural spectral cue was preserved. All subjects showed systematic mislocalizations in both the true right and true interaural spectral conditions which was absent in their control localization performance. The analysis of the different cues along with the subjects&apos; localization responses suggests there are significant differences in the use of the monaural and interaural spectral cues and that the auditory system&apos;s reliance on the spectral cues varies with the sound condition.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
