<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Redundancy and Dimensionality Reduction in Sparse-Distributed Representations of Natural Objects in Terms of Their Local Features</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Penio</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Penev</surname></persName>
							<email>penev@rockefeller.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory of Computational Neuroscience The Rockefeller University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1230 York Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>10021</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Redundancy and Dimensionality Reduction in Sparse-Distributed Representations of Natural Objects in Terms of Their Local Features</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Low-dimensional representations are key to solving problems in high-level vision, such as face compression and recognition. Factorial coding strategies for reducing the redundancy present in natural images on the basis of their second-order statistics have been successful in accounting for both psychophysical and neurophysiological properties of early vision. Class-specific representations are presumably formed later, at the higher-level stages of cortical processing. Here we show that when retinotopic factorial codes are derived for ensembles of natural objects, such as human faces, not only redundancy, but also dimensionality is reduced. We also show that objects are built from parts in a non-Gaussian fashion which allows these local-feature codes to have dimensionalities that are substantially lower than the respective Nyquist sampling rates.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
