<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A productive, systematic framework for the representation of visual structure</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shimon</forename><surname>Edelman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Brain and Neural Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell University Ithaca</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University Providence</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>Box 1843</postBox>
									<postCode>14853-7601, 02912</postCode>
									<region>NY, RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uris</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Brain and Neural Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell University Ithaca</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University Providence</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>Box 1843</postBox>
									<postCode>14853-7601, 02912</postCode>
									<region>NY, RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Intrator</surname></persName>
							<email>N athan_Intrator@brown. edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute for Brain and Neural Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Cornell University Ithaca</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Brown University Providence</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>Box 1843</postBox>
									<postCode>14853-7601, 02912</postCode>
									<region>NY, RI</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A productive, systematic framework for the representation of visual structure</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We describe a unified framework for the understanding of structure representation in primate vision. A model derived from this framework is shown to be effectively systematic in that it has the ability to interpret and associate together objects that are related through a rearrangement of common &quot;middle-scale&quot; parts, represented as image fragments. The model addresses the same concerns as previous work on compositional representation through the use of what+where receptive fields and attentional gain modulation. It does not require prior exposure to the individual parts, and avoids the need for abstract symbolic binding. 1 The problem of structure representation The focus of theoretical discussion in visual object processing has recently started to shift from problems of recognition and categorization to the representation of object structure. Although view-or appearance-based solutions for these problems proved effective on a variety of object classes [1], the &quot;holistic&quot; nature of this approach-the lack of explicit representation of relational structure-limits its appeal as a general framework for visual representation [2]. The main challenges in the processing of structure are productivity and system-aticity, two traits commonly attributed to human cognition. A visual system is productive if it is open-ended, that is, if it can deal effectively with a potentially infinite set of objects. A visual representation is systematic if a well-defined change in the spatial configuration of the object (e.g., swapping top and bottom parts) causes a principled change in the representation (e.g., the interchange of the representations of top and bottom parts [3, 2]). A solution commonly offered to the twin problems of productivity and systematicity is compositional representation, in which symbols standing for generic parts drawn from a small repertoire are bound together by categorical symbolically coded relations [4].</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
