<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Keeping flexible active contours on track using Metropolis updates</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Trausti</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Kristjansson</surname></persName>
							<email>tt kr i s tj @uwa te r l oo . ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Waterloo</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Keeping flexible active contours on track using Metropolis updates</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Brendan J. Frey University of Waterloo f r ey@uwate r l oo. ca Condensation, a form of likelihood-weighted particle filtering, has been successfully used to infer the shapes of highly constrained &quot;active&quot; contours in video sequences. However, when the contours are highly flexible (e.g. for tracking fingers of a hand), a computationally burdensome number of particles is needed to successfully approximate the contour distribution. We show how the Metropolis algorithm can be used to update a particle set representing a distribution over contours at each frame in a video sequence. We compare this method to condensation using a video sequence that requires highly flexible contours, and show that the new algorithm performs dramatically better that the condensation algorithm. We discuss the incorporation of this method into the &quot;active contour&quot; framework where a shape-subspace is used constrain shape variation.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
