<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:14+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">474 OPTIMIZA nON WITH ARTIFICIAL NEURAL NETWORK SYSTEMS: A MAPPING PRINCIPLE AND A COMPARISON TO GRADIENT BASED METHODS t</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harrison</forename><forename type="middle">Monfook</forename><surname>Leong</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Research Institute for Advanced Computer Science NASA Ames Research Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>230-5 Moffett Field</addrLine>
									<postCode>94035</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">474 OPTIMIZA nON WITH ARTIFICIAL NEURAL NETWORK SYSTEMS: A MAPPING PRINCIPLE AND A COMPARISON TO GRADIENT BASED METHODS t</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>General formulae for mapping optimization problems into systems of ordinary differential equations associated with artificial neural networks are presented. A comparison is made to optimization using gradient-search methods. The perfonnance measure is the settling time from an initial state to a target state. A simple analytical example illustrates a situation where dynamical systems representing artificial neural network methods would settle faster than those representing gradient-search. Settling time was investigated for a more complicated optimization problem using computer simulations. The problem was a simplified version of a problem in medical imaging: determining loci of cerebral activity from electromagnetic measurements at the scalp. The simulations showed that gradient based systems typically settled 50 to 100 times faster than systems based on current neural network optimization methods. INTRODUCTION Solving optimization problems with systems of equations based on neurobiological principles has recently received a great deal of attention. Much of this interest began when an artificial neural network was devised to find near-optimal solutions to an np-complete problem 13. Since then, a number of problems have been mapped into the same artificial neural network and variations of it 10.13,14,17.18,19.21,23.24. In this paper, a unifying principle underlying these mappings is derived for systems of first to nth-order ordinary differential equations. This mapping principle bears similarity to the mathematical tools used to generate optimization methods based on the gradient. In view of this, it seemed important to compare the optimization efficiency of dynamical systems constructed by the neural network mapping principle with dynamical systems constructed from the gradient. .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
