<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Laplacian Eigenmaps and Spectral Techniques for Embedding and Clustering</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mikhail</forename><surname>Belkin</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Depts. of Mathematics and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Chicago Hyde Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60637</postCode>
									<settlement>Chicago</settlement>
									<region>IL</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Partha</forename><surname>Niyogi</surname></persName>
							<email>niyogi@cs.uchicago.edu)</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Depts. of Mathematics and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The University of Chicago Hyde Park</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60637</postCode>
									<settlement>Chicago</settlement>
									<region>IL</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Laplacian Eigenmaps and Spectral Techniques for Embedding and Clustering</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Drawing on the correspondence between the graph Laplacian, the Laplace-Beltrami op erator on a manifold , and the connections to the heat equation , we propose a geometrically motivated algorithm for constructing a representation for data sampled from a low dimensional manifold embedded in a higher dimensional space. The algorithm provides a computationally efficient approach to non-linear dimensionality reduction that has locality preserving properties and a natural connection to clustering. Several applications are considered. In many areas of artificial intelligence, information retrieval and data mining, one is often confronted with intrinsically low dimensional data lying in a very high dimensional space. For example, gray scale n x n images of a fixed object taken with a moving camera yield data points in rn: n2. However , the intrinsic dimensionality of the space of all images of t he same object is the number of degrees of freedom of the camera-in fact the space has the natural structure of a manifold embedded in rn: n2. While there is a large body of work on dimensionality reduction in general, most existing approaches do not explicitly take into account the structure of the manifold on which the data may possibly reside. Recently, there has been some interest (Tenenbaum et aI, 2000 ; Roweis and Saul, 2000) in the problem of developing low dimensional representations of data in this particular context. In this paper , we present a new algorithm and an accompanying framework of analysis for geometrically motivated dimensionality reduction. The core algorithm is very simple, has a few local computations and one sparse eigenvalu e problem. The solution reflects th e intrinsic geom etric structure of the manifold. Th e justification comes from the role of the Laplacian op erator in providing an optimal emb edding. Th e Laplacian of the graph obtained from the data points may be viewed as an approximation to the Laplace-Beltrami operator defined on the manifold. The emb edding maps for the data come from approximations to a natural map that is defined on the entire manifold. The framework of analysis</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
