<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative Direction for Kernel Classifiers</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Polina</forename><surname>Golland</surname></persName>
							<email>polina@ai.mit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Technology Cambridge</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Lab Massachusetts</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Discriminative Direction for Kernel Classifiers</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In many scientific and engineering applications, detecting and understanding differences between two groups of examples can be reduced to a classical problem of training a classifier for labeling new examples while making as few mistakes as possible. In the traditional classification setting, the resulting classifier is rarely analyzed in terms of the properties of the input data captured by the discriminative model. However , such analysis is crucial if we want to understand and visualize the detected differences. We propose an approach to interpretation of the statistical model in the original feature space that allows us to argue about the model in terms of the relevant changes to the input vectors. For each point in the input space, we define a discriminative direction to be the direction that moves the point towards the other class while introducing as little irrelevant change as possible with respect to the classifier function. We derive the discriminative direction for kernel-based classifiers, demonstrate the technique on several examples and briefly discuss its use in the statistical shape analysis, an application that originally motivated this work.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
