<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Eye movements and the maturation of cortical orientation selectivity</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Rucci</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Cognitive and Neural Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Boston University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02215</postCode>
									<settlement>Boston</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Antonino</forename><surname>Casile</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Scuola Superiore S. Anna</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Pisa</settlement>
									<country key="IT">Italy</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Eye movements and the maturation of cortical orientation selectivity</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Neural activity appears to be a crucial component for shaping the receptive fields of cortical simple cells into adjacent, oriented subregions alternately receiving ON-and OFF-center excitatory geniculate inputs. It is known that the orientation selective responses of V1 neurons are refined by visual experience. After eye opening, the spatiotemporal structure of neural activity in the early stages of the visual pathway depends both on the visual environment and on how the environment is scanned. We have used computational modeling to investigate how eye movements might affect the refinement of the orientation tuning of simple cells in the presence of a Hebbian scheme of synaptic plasticity. Levels of correlation between the activity of simulated cells were examined while natural scenes were scanned so as to model sequences of saccades and fixational eye movements, such as microsaccades, tremor and ocular drift. The specific patterns of activity required for a quantitatively accurate development of simple cell receptive fields with segregated ON and OFF subregions were observed during fixational eye movements, but not in the presence of saccades or with static presentation of natural visual input. These results suggest an important role for the eye movements occurring during visual fixation in the refinement of orientation selectivity.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
