<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Face Recognition Using Kernel Methods</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ming-Hsuan</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<email>myang@hra.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Honda Fundamental Research Labs Mountain View</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94041</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Face Recognition Using Kernel Methods</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Principal Component Analysis and Fisher Linear Discriminant methods have demonstrated their success in face detection, recognition , and tracking. The representation in these subspace methods is based on second order statistics of the image set, and does not address higher order statistical dependencies such as the relationships among three or more pixels. Recently Higher Order Statistics and Independent Component Analysis (ICA) have been used as informative low dimensional representations for visual recognition. In this paper, we investigate the use of Kernel Principal Component Analysis and Kernel Fisher Linear Discriminant for learning low dimensional representations for face recognition, which we call Kernel Eigenface and Kernel Fisherface methods. While Eigenface and Fisherface methods aim to find projection directions based on the second order correlation of samples, Kernel Eigenface and Kernel Fisherface methods provide generalizations which take higher order correlations into account. We compare the performance of kernel methods with Eigenface, Fisherface and ICA-based methods for face recognition with variation in pose, scale, lighting and expression. Experimental results show that kernel methods provide better representations and achieve lower error rates for face recognition.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
