<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian morphometry of hippocampal cells suggests same-cell somatodendritic repulsion</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giorgio</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ascoli</surname></persName>
							<email>ascoli@gmu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Krasnow Institute for Advanced Study at George Mason University Fairfax</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>22030-4444</postCode>
									<region>VA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alexei</forename><surname>Samsonovich</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Krasnow Institute for Advanced Study at George Mason University Fairfax</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>22030-4444</postCode>
									<region>VA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Bayesian morphometry of hippocampal cells suggests same-cell somatodendritic repulsion</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>1</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Visual inspection of neurons suggests that dendritic orientation may be determined both by internal constraints (e.g. membrane tension) and by external vector fields (e.g. neurotrophic gradients). For example, basal dendrites of pyramidal cells appear nicely fan-out. This regular orientation is hard to justify completely with a general tendency to grow straight, given the zigzags observed experimentally. Instead, dendrites could (A) favor a fixed (&quot;external&quot;) direction, or (B) repel from their own soma. To investigate these possibilities quantitatively, reconstructed hippocampal cells were subjected to Bayesian analysis. The statistical model combined linearly factors A and B, as well as the tendency to grow straight. For all morphological classes, B was found to be significantly positive and consistently greater than A. In addition, when dendrites were artificially reoriented according to this model, the resulting structures closely resembled real morphologies. These results suggest that somatodendritic repulsion may play a role in determining dendritic orientation. Since hippocampal cells are very densely packed and their dendritic trees highly overlap, the repulsion must be cell-specific. We discuss possible mechanisms underlying such specificity.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
