<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Temporal Coherence, Natural Image Sequences, and the Visual Cortex</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jarmo</forename><surname>Hurri</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Neural Networks Research Centre Helsinki University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O.Box 9800</postBox>
									<postCode>02015 HUT</postCode>
									<country key="FI">Finland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aapo</forename><surname>Hyvärinen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Neural Networks Research Centre Helsinki University of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O.Box 9800</postBox>
									<postCode>02015 HUT</postCode>
									<country key="FI">Finland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Temporal Coherence, Natural Image Sequences, and the Visual Cortex</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We show that two important properties of the primary visual cortex emerge when the principle of temporal coherence is applied to natural image sequences. The properties are simple-cell-like receptive fields and complex-cell-like pooling of simple cell outputs, which emerge when we apply two different approaches to temporal coherence. In the first approach we extract receptive fields whose outputs are as temporally coherent as possible. This approach yields simple-cell-like receptive fields (oriented, localized, multiscale). Thus, temporal coherence is an alternative to sparse coding in modeling the emergence of simple cell receptive fields. The second approach is based on a two-layer statistical generative model of natural image sequences. In addition to modeling the temporal coherence of individual simple cells, this model includes inter-cell temporal dependencies. Estimation of this model from natural data yields both simple-cell-like receptive fields, and complex-cell-like pooling of simple cell outputs. In this completely unsupervised learning, both layers of the generative model are estimated simultaneously from scratch. This is a significant improvement on earlier statistical models of early vision, where only one layer has been learned, and others have been fixed a priori.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
