<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Kernel-based Extraction of Slow Features: Complex Cells Learn Disparity and Trans-lation Invariance from Natural Images</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Bray</surname></persName>
							<email>bray@loria.fr, dmartine@loria.jr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">CORTEX Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">LORIA-INRIA</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Nancy</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dominique</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">CORTEX Group</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">LORIA-INRIA</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Nancy</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Kernel-based Extraction of Slow Features: Complex Cells Learn Disparity and Trans-lation Invariance from Natural Images</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In Slow Feature Analysis (SFA [1]), it has been demonstrated that high-order invariant properties can be extracted by projecting inputs into a nonlinear space and computing the slowest changing features in this space; this has been proposed as a simple general model for learning nonlinear invariances in the visual system. However , this method is highly constrained by the curse of dimension-ality which limits it to simple theoretical simulations. This paper demonstrates that by using a different but closely-related objective function for extracting slowly varying features ([2, 3]), and then exploiting the kernel trick, this curse can be avoided. Using this new method we show that both the complex cell properties of translation invariance and disparity coding can be learnt simultaneously from natural images when complex cells are driven by simple cells also learnt from the image. The notion of maximising an objective function based upon the temporal predictability of output has been progressively applied in modelling the development of invariances in the visual system. F6ldiak used it indirectly via a Hebbian trace rule for modelling the development of translation invariance in complex cells [4] (closely related to many other models [5,6,7]); this rule has been used to maximise invariance as one component of a hierarchical system for object and face recognition [8]. On the other hand, similar functions have been maximised directly in networks for extracting linear [2] and nonlinear [9, 1] visual invariances. Direct maximisation of such functions have recently been used to model complex cells [10] and as an alternative to maximising sparseness/independence in modelling simple cells [11]. Slow Feature Analysis [1] combines many of the best properties of these methods to provide a good general nonlinear model. That is, it uses an objective function that minimises the first-order temporal derivative of the outputs; it provides a closed-form solution which maximises this function by projecting inputs into a nonlinear</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
