<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Effect of Singularities in a Learning Machine when the True Parameters Do Not Lie on Such Singularities</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sumio</forename><surname>Watanabe</surname></persName>
							<email>E-mail: swatanab@pi.titech.ac.jp</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Precision and Intelligence Laboratory Shun-ichi Amari Laboratory for Mathematical Neuroscience</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tokyo Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Midori-ku</addrLine>
									<postCode>4259, 226-8503</postCode>
									<settlement>Nagatsuta, Yokohama</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">RIKEN Brain Science Institute Hirosawa</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2-1, Wako-shi</addrLine>
									<postCode>351-0198</postCode>
									<settlement>Saitama</settlement>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Effect of Singularities in a Learning Machine when the True Parameters Do Not Lie on Such Singularities</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A lot of learning machines with hidden variables used in information science have singularities in their parameter spaces. At singularities, the Fisher information matrix becomes degenerate, resulting that the learning theory of regular statistical models does not hold. Recently, it was proven that, if the true parameter is contained in singularities, then the coefficient of the Bayes generalization error is equal to the pole of the zeta function of the Kullback information. In this paper, under the condition that the true parameter is almost but not contained in singularities, we show two results. (1) If the dimension of the parameter from inputs to hidden units is not larger than three, then there exits a region of true parameters where the generalization error is larger than those of regular models, however, if otherwise, then for any true parameter, the generalization error is smaller than those of regular models. (2) The symmetry of the generalization error and the training error does not hold in singular models in general.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
