<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Meiosis Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">Jose</forename><surname>Hanson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Cognitive Science Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Learning and Knowledge Acquisition Group Siemens Research Center Princeton</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540, 08542</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ, NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Meiosis Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>534 Hanson</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Meiosis Networks 533 A central problem in connectionist modelling is the control of network and architectural resources during learning. In the present approach, weights reflect a coarse prediction history as coded by a distribution of values and parameterized in the mean and standard deviation of these weight distributions. Weight updates are a function of both the mean and standard deviation of each connection in the network and vary as a function of the error signal (&quot;stochastic delta rule&quot;; Hanson, 1990). Consequently, the weights maintain information on their central tendency and their &quot;uncertainty&quot; in prediction. Such information is useful in establishing a policy concerning the size of the nodal complexity of the network and growth of new nodes. For example, during problem solving the present network can undergo &quot;meiosis&quot;, producing two nodes where there was one &quot;overtaxed&quot; node as measured by its coefficient of variation. It is shown in a number of benchmark problems that meiosis networks can find minimal architectures, reduce computational complexity, and overall increase the efficiency of the representation learning interaction.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
