<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">702 Obradovic and Pclrberry Analog Neural Networks of Limited Precision I: Computing with Multilinear Threshold Functions (Preliminary Version)</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Zoran</forename><surname>Obradovic</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Penn State University. University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>Park. Pa. 16802</postBox>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Parberry</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Penn State University. University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>Park. Pa. 16802</postBox>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">702 Obradovic and Pclrberry Analog Neural Networks of Limited Precision I: Computing with Multilinear Threshold Functions (Preliminary Version)</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Experimental evidence has shown analog neural networks to be ex-~mely fault-tolerant; in particular. their performance does not appear to be significantly impaired when precision is limited. Analog neurons with limited precision essentially compute k-ary weighted multilinear threshold functions. which divide R&quot; into k regions with k-l hyperplanes. The behaviour of k-ary neural networks is investigated. There is no canonical set of threshold values for k&gt;3. although they exist for binary and ternary neural networks. The weights can be made integers of only 0 «z +k) log (z +k » bits. where z is the number of processors. without increasing hardware or running time. The weights can be made ±1 while increasing running time by a constant multiple and hardware by a small polynomial in z and k. Binary neurons can be used if the running time is allowed to increase by a larger constant multiple and the hardware is allowed to increase by a slightly larger polynomial in z and k. Any symmetric k-ary function can be computed in constant depth and size o (n k-1 /(k-2)!). and any k-ary function can be computed in constant depth and size 0 (nk&quot;). The alternating neural networks of Olafsson and Abu-Mostafa. and the quantized neural networks of Fleisher are closely related to this model.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
