<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:15+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Iterative scaled trust-region learning in Krylov subspaces via Pearlmutter&apos;s implicit sparse Hessian-vector multiply</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eiji</forename><surname>Mizutani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Mathematics and Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Tsing Hua University Hsinchu</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>300</postCode>
									<country>TAIWAN R.O.C</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Demmel</surname></persName>
							<email>demmel@cs.berkeley.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California at Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Iterative scaled trust-region learning in Krylov subspaces via Pearlmutter&apos;s implicit sparse Hessian-vector multiply</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The online incremental gradient (or backpropagation) algorithm is widely considered to be the fastest method for solving large-scale neural-network (NN) learning problems. In contrast, we show that an appropriately implemented iterative batch-mode (or block-mode) learning method can be much faster. For example, it is three times faster in the UCI letter classification problem (26 outputs, 16,000 data items, 6,066 parameters with a two-hidden-layer multilayer perceptron) and 353 times faster in a nonlinear regression problem arising in color recipe prediction (10 outputs, 1,000 data items, 2,210 parameters with a neuro-fuzzy modular network). The three principal innovative ingredients in our algorithm are the following: First, we use scaled trust-region regularization with inner-outer iteration to solve the associated &quot;overdetermined&quot; nonlinear least squares problem, where the inner iteration performs a truncated (or inexact) Newton method. Second, we employ Pearlmutter&apos;s implicit sparse Hessian matrix-vector multiply algorithm to construct the Krylov subspaces used to solve for the truncated New-ton update. Third, we exploit sparsity (for preconditioning) in the matrices resulting from the NNs having many outputs.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
