<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Recurrent Model of Orientation Maps with Simple and Complex Cells</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Merolla</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Bioengineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kwabena</forename><surname>Boahen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Bioengineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Pennsylvania Philadelphia</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>19104</postCode>
									<region>PA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Recurrent Model of Orientation Maps with Simple and Complex Cells</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We describe a neuromorphic chip that utilizes transistor heterogeneity, introduced by the fabrication process, to generate orientation maps similar to those imaged in vivo. Our model consists of a recurrent network of excitatory and inhibitory cells in parallel with a push-pull stage. Similar to a previous model the recurrent network displays hotspots of activity that give rise to visual feature maps. Unlike previous work, however, the map for orientation does not depend on the sign of contrast. Instead, sign-independent cells driven by both ON and OFF channels anchor the map, while push-pull interactions give rise to sign-preserving cells. These two groups of orientation-selective cells are similar to complex and simple cells observed in V1. 1 Orientation Maps Neurons in visual areas 1 and 2 (V1 and V2) are selectively tuned for a number of visual features, the most pronounced feature being orientation. Orientation preference of individual cells varies across the two-dimensional surface of the cortex in a stereotyped manner, as revealed by electrophysiology [1] and optical imaging studies [2]. The origin of these preferred orientation (PO) maps is debated, but experiments demonstrate that they exist in the absence of visual experience [3]. To the dismay of advocates of Hebbian learning, these results suggest that the initial appearance of PO maps rely on neural mechanisms oblivious to input correlations. Here, we propose a model that accounts for observed PO maps based on innate noise in neuron thresholds and synaptic currents. The network is implemented in silicon where heterogeneity is as ubiquitous as it is in biology. 2 Patterned Activity Model Ernst et al. have previously described a 2D rate model that can account for the origin of visual maps [4]. Individual units in their network receive isotropic feedforward input from the geniculate and recurrent connections from neighboring</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
