<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Effects of Circuit Integration on a Feature Map Vector Quantizer</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jim</forename><surname>Lviann</surname></persName>
							<email>email: mann@vlsi.ll.mit.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">MIT Lincoln Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>244 Wood St. Lexington</addrLine>
									<postCode>02173</postCode>
									<region>~IA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Effects of Circuit Integration on a Feature Map Vector Quantizer</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>226 Mann</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The effects of parameter modifications imposed by hardware constraints on a self-organizing feature map algorithm were examined. Performance was measured by the error rate of a speech recognition system which included this algorithm as part of the front-end processing. System parameters which were varied included weight (connection strength) quantization, adap tation quantization, distance measures and circuit approximations which include device characteristics and process variability. Experiments using the TI isolated word database for 16 speakers demonstrated degradation in performance when weight quantization fell below 8 bits. The competitive nature of the algorithm rela..xes constraints on uniformity and linearity which makes it an excellent candidate for a fully ana-log circuit implementation. Prototype circuits have been fabricated and characterized following the constraints established through the simulation efforts.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
