<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">How to Combine Expert (or Novice) Advice when Actions Impact the Environment</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><surname>Pucci De Farias</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Mechanical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">IBM Almaden Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>650 Harry Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>02139, K53-B2, 95120</postCode>
									<settlement>San Jose</settlement>
									<region>MA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nimrod</forename><surname>Megiddo</surname></persName>
							<email>megiddo@almaden.ibm.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Mechanical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">IBM Almaden Research Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>650 Harry Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>02139, K53-B2, 95120</postCode>
									<settlement>San Jose</settlement>
									<region>MA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">How to Combine Expert (or Novice) Advice when Actions Impact the Environment</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The so-called &quot;experts algorithms&quot; constitute a methodology for choosing actions repeatedly, when the rewards depend both on the choice of action and on the unknown current state of the environment. An experts algorithm has access to a set of strategies (&quot;experts&quot;), each of which may recommend which action to choose. The algorithm learns how to combine the recommendations of individual experts so that, in the long run, for any fixed sequence of states of the environment, it does as well as the best expert would have done relative to the same sequence. This methodology may not be suitable for situations where the evolution of states of the environment depends on past chosen actions, as is usually the case, for example, in a repeated non-zero-sum game. A new experts algorithm is presented and analyzed in the context of repeated games. It is shown that asymptotically, under certain conditions, it performs as well as the best available expert. This algorithm is quite different from previously proposed experts algorithms. It represents a shift from the paradigms of regret minimization and myopic optimization to consideration of the long-term effect of a player&apos;s actions on the opponent&apos;s actions or the environment. The importance of this shift is demonstrated by the fact that this algorithm is capable of inducing cooperation in the repeated Prisoner&apos;s Dilemma game, whereas previous experts algorithms converge to the suboptimal non-cooperative play.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
