<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Constraining a Bayesian Model of Human Visual Speed Perception</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alan</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Stocker</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Neural Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Howard Hughes Medical Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences New York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">U.S.A</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eero</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Simoncelli</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Neural Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Howard Hughes Medical Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences New York University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">U.S.A</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Constraining a Bayesian Model of Human Visual Speed Perception</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>It has been demonstrated that basic aspects of human visual motion perception are qualitatively consistent with a Bayesian estimation framework , where the prior probability distribution on velocity favors slow speeds. Here, we present a refined probabilistic model that can account for the typical trial-to-trial variabilities observed in psychophysical speed perception experiments. We also show that data from such experiments can be used to constrain both the likelihood and prior functions of the model. Specifically, we measured matching speeds and thresholds in a two-alternative forced choice speed discrimination task. Parametric fits to the data reveal that the likelihood function is well approximated by a LogNormal distribution with a characteristic contrast-dependent variance , and that the prior distribution on velocity exhibits significantly heavier tails than a Gaussian, and approximately follows a power-law function. Humans do not perceive visual motion veridically. Various psychophysical experiments have shown that the perceived speed of visual stimuli is affected by stimulus contrast, with low contrast stimuli being perceived to move slower than high contrast ones [1, 2]. Computational models have been suggested that can qualitatively explain these perceptual effects. Commonly, they assume the perception of visual motion to be optimal either within a deterministic framework with a regularization constraint that biases the solution toward zero motion [3, 4], or within a probabilistic framework of Bayesian estimation with a prior that favors slow velocities [5, 6]. The solutions resulting from these two frameworks are similar (and in some cases identical), but the probabilistic framework provides a more principled formulation of the problem in terms of meaningful probabilistic components. Specifically, Bayesian approaches rely on a likelihood function that expresses the relationship between the noisy measurements and the quantity to be estimated, and a prior distribution that expresses the probability of encountering any particular value of that quantity. A probabilistic model can also provide a richer description, by defining a full probability density over the set of possible &quot;percepts&quot;, rather than just a single value. Numerous analyses of psychophysical experiments have made use of such distributions within the framework of signal detection theory in order to model perceptual behavior [7]. Previous work has shown that an ideal Bayesian observer model based on Gaussian forms</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
