<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Weather Using a Genetic Memory 455 Predicting Weather Using a Genetic Memory: a Combi-nation of Kanerva&apos;s Sparse Distributed Memory with Holland&apos;s Genetic Algorithms</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Research Institute for Advanced Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">NASA Ames Research Center Moffett Field</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>230-5, 94035</postCode>
									<region>MS, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Weather Using a Genetic Memory 455 Predicting Weather Using a Genetic Memory: a Combi-nation of Kanerva&apos;s Sparse Distributed Memory with Holland&apos;s Genetic Algorithms</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Kanerva&apos;s sparse distributed memory (SDM) is an associative-memory model based on the mathematical properties of high-dimensional binary address spaces. Holland&apos;s genetic algorithms are a search technique for high-dimensional spaces inspired by evolutionary processes of DNA. &quot;Genetic Memory&quot; is a hybrid of the above two systems, in which the memory uses a genetic algorithm to dynamically recon-figure its physical storage locations to reflect correlations between the stored addresses and data. For example, when presented with raw weather station data, the Genetic Memory discovers specific features in the weather data which correlate well with upcoming rain, and reconfigures the memory to utilize this information effectively. This architecture is designed to maximize the ability of the system to scale-up to handle real-world problems.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
