<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Theories Of Access Consciousness</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Colagrosso</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Institute of Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Colorado School of Mines Golden</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80401</postCode>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mozer</surname></persName>
							<email>mozer@colorado.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309</postCode>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Theories Of Access Consciousness</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Theories of access consciousness address how it is that some mental states but not others are available for evaluation, choice behavior, and verbal report. Farah, O&apos;Reilly, and Vecera (1994) argue that quality of representation is critical; De-haene, Sergent, and Changeux (2003) argue that the ability to communicate representations is critical. We present a probabilistic information transmission or PIT model that suggests both of these conditions are essential for access consciousness. Having successfully modeled data from the repetition priming literature in the past, we use the PIT model to account for data from two experiments on subliminal priming, showing that the model produces priming even in the absence of accessibility and reportability of internal states. The model provides a mechanistic basis for understanding the dissociation of priming and awareness. Philosophy has made many attempts to identify distinct aspects of consciousness. Perhaps the most famous effort is Block&apos;s (1995) delineation of phenomenal and access consciousness. Phenomenal consciousness has to do with &quot;what it is like&quot; to experience chocolate or a pin prick. Access consciousness refers to internal states whose content is &quot;(1) inferen-tially promiscuous, i.e., poised to be used as a premise in reasoning, (2) poised for control of action, and (3) poised for rational control of speech.&quot; (p. 230) The scientific study of consciousness has exploded in the past six years, and an important catalyst for this explosion has been the decision to focus on the problem of access consciousness: how is it that some mental states but not others become available for evaluation, choice behavior, verbal report, and storage in working memory. Another reason for the recent explosion of consciousness research is the availability of functional imaging techniques to explore differences in brain activation between conscious and unconscious states, as well as the development of clever psychological experiments that show that a stimulus that is not consciously perceived can nonetheless influence cognition, which we describe shortly.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
