<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:16+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Common-Frame Model for Object Recognition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Moreels</surname></persName>
							<email>pmoreels,perona@vision.caltech.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">California Insitute of Technology -Pasadena CA91125</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pietro</forename><surname>Perona</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">California Insitute of Technology -Pasadena CA91125</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Common-Frame Model for Object Recognition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A generative probabilistic model for objects in images is presented. An object consists of a constellation of features. Feature appearance and pose are modeled probabilistically. Scene images are generated by drawing a set of objects from a given database, with random clutter sprinkled on the remaining image surface. Occlusion is allowed. We study the case where features from the same object share a common reference frame. Moreover, parameters for shape and appearance densities are shared across features. This is to be contrasted with previous work on probabilistic &apos;constellation&apos; models where features depend on each other, and each feature and model have different pose and appearance statistics [1, 2]. These two differences allow us to build models containing hundreds of features, as well as to train each model from a single example. Our model may also be thought of as a probabilistic revisitation of Lowe&apos;s model [3, 4]. We propose an efficient entropy-minimization inference algorithm that constructs the best interpretation of a scene as a collection of objects and clutter. We test our ideas with experiments on two image databases. We compare with Lowe&apos;s algorithm and demonstrate better performance, in particular in presence of large amounts of background clutter.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
