<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Shared Information and Coordinated Activity in Neuronal Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><forename type="middle">Lisa</forename><surname>Klinkner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Statistics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Statistics Department Carnegie</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan Ann Arbor</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48109, 15213, 94118</postCode>
									<region>MI, PA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Rohilla</forename><surname>Cosma</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Statistics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Statistics Department Carnegie</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan Ann Arbor</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48109, 15213, 94118</postCode>
									<region>MI, PA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Shalizi</surname></persName>
							<email>kshalizi@umich.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Statistics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Statistics Department Carnegie</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan Ann Arbor</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48109, 15213, 94118</postCode>
									<region>MI, PA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Marcelo</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Camperi</surname></persName>
							<email>camperi@usfca.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Statistics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Statistics Department Carnegie</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Michigan Ann Arbor</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>48109, 15213, 94118</postCode>
									<region>MI, PA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Measuring Shared Information and Coordinated Activity in Neuronal Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Most nervous systems encode information about stimuli in the responding activity of large neuronal networks. This activity often manifests itself as dynamically coordinated sequences of action potentials. Since multiple electrode recordings are now a standard tool in neuroscience research, it is important to have a measure of such network-wide behav-ioral coordination and information sharing, applicable to multiple neural spike train data. We propose a new statistic, informational coherence, which measures how much better one unit can be predicted by knowing the dynamical state of another. We argue informational coherence is a measure of association and shared information which is superior to traditional pairwise measures of synchronization and correlation. To find the dynamical states, we use a recently-introduced algorithm which reconstructs effective state spaces from stochastic time series. We then extend the pairwise measure to a multivariate analysis of the network by estimating the network multi-information. We illustrate our method by testing it on a detailed model of the transition from gamma to beta rhythms. Much of the most important information in neural systems is shared over multiple neu-rons or cortical areas, in such forms as population codes and distributed representations [1]. On behavioral time scales, neural information is stored in temporal patterns of activity as opposed to static markers; therefore, as information is shared between neurons or brain regions, it is physically instantiated as coordination between entire sequences of neural spikes. Furthermore, neural systems and regions of the brain often require coordinated neural activity to perform important functions; acting in concert requires multiple neurons or cortical areas to share information [2]. Thus, if we want to measure the dynamic network-wide behavior of neurons and test hypotheses about them, we need reliable, practical methods to detect and quantify behavioral coordination and the associated information sharing across multiple neural units. These would be especially useful in testing ideas about how particular forms of coordination relate to distributed coding (e.g., that of [3]). Current techniques to analyze relations among spike trains handle only pairs of neurons, so we further need a method which is extendible to analyze the coordination in the network, system, or region as a whole. Here we propose a new measure of behavioral coordination and information sharing, informational coherence, based on the notion of dynamical state. Section 1 argues that coordinated behavior in neural systems is often not captured by exist</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
