<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">524 BASINS OF ATTRACTION FOR ELECTRONIC NEURAL NETWORKS</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Marcus</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Division of Applied Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Westervelt</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Division of Applied Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Physics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<settlement>Cambridge</settlement>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">524 BASINS OF ATTRACTION FOR ELECTRONIC NEURAL NETWORKS</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We have studied the basins of attraction for fixed point and oscillatory attractors in an electronic analog neural network. Basin measurement circuitry periodically opens the network feedback loop, loads raster-scanned initial conditions and examines the resulting attractor. Plotting the basins for fixed points (memories), we show that overloading an associative memory network leads to irregular basin shapes. The network also includes analog time delay circuitry, and we have shown that delay in symmetric networks can introduce basins for oscillatory attractors. Conditions leading to oscillation are related to the presence of frustration; reducing frustration by diluting the connections can stabilize a delay network. (1)-INTRODUCTION The dynamical system formed from an interconnected network of nonlinear neuron-like elements can perform useful parallel computation l-5. Recent progress in controlling the dynamics has focussed on algorithms for encoding the location of fixed pOints 1 ,4 and on the stability of the flow to fixed points 3 • 5-8. An equally important aspect of the dynamics is the structure of the basins of attraction, which describe the location of all pOints in initial condition space which flow to a particular attractor 10. 22. In a useful associative memory, an initial state should lead reliably to the &quot;closest&quot; memory. This requirement suggests that a well-behaved basin of attraction should evenly surround its attractor and have a smooth and regular shape. One dimensional basin maps plotting &quot;pull in&quot; probability against Hamming distance from an attract or do not reveal the shape of the basin in the high dimensional space of initial states 9. 19. Recently, a numerical study of a Hopfield network with discrete time and two-state neurons showed rough and irregular basin shapes in a two dimensional Hamming space, suggesting that the high dimensional basin has a complicated structure 10. It is not known how the basin shapes change with the size of the network and the connection rule. We have investigated the basins of attraction in a network with continuous state dynamics by building an electronic neural network with eight variable gain sigmoid neurons and a three level (+,0,-) interconnection matrix. We have also built circuitry that can map out the basins of attraction in two dimensional slices of initial state space (Fig .1). The network and the basin measurements are described in section 2.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
