<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Discovering the Structure of a Reactive Environment by Exploration 439 Discovering the Structure of a Reactive Environment by Exploration</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mozer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Computer Science and Institute of Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">DepartmentofCompu~ and Infonnation Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado Boulder</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309-0430</postCode>
									<settlement>ABSTRACT</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonatban</forename><surname>Bachrach</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Massachusetts Amherst</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>01003</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Discovering the Structure of a Reactive Environment by Exploration 439 Discovering the Structure of a Reactive Environment by Exploration</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Consider a robot wandering around an unfamiliar environment. performing actions and sensing the resulting environmental states. The robot&apos;s task is to construct an internal model of its environment. a model that will allow it to predict the consequences of its actions and to determine what sequences of actions to take to reach particular goal states. Rivest and Schapire (1987&amp;, 1987b; Schapire. 1988) have studied this problem and have designed a symbolic algorithm to strategically explore and infer the structure of &quot;finite state&quot; environments. The heart of this algorithm is a clever representation of the environment called an update graph. We have developed a connectionist implementation of the update graph using a highly-specialized network architecture. With back propagation learning and a trivial exploration strategy-choosing random actions the connectionist network can outperfonn the Rivest and Schapire algorithm on simple problems. The network has the additional strength that it can accommodate stochastic environments. Perhaps the greatest virtue of the connectionist approach is that it suggests generalizations of the update graph representation that do not arise from a traditional, symbolic perspective.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
