<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Cortically-Plausible Inverse Problem Solving Method Applied to Recognizing Static and Kinematic 3D Objects</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Arathorn</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Computational Biology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Montana State University Bozeman</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">General Intelligence Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>59717</postCode>
									<region>MT</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Cortically-Plausible Inverse Problem Solving Method Applied to Recognizing Static and Kinematic 3D Objects</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent neurophysiological evidence suggests the ability to interpret biological motion is facilitated by a neuronal &quot;mirror system&quot; which maps visual inputs to the pre-motor cortex. If the common architecture and circuitry of the cortices is taken to imply a common computation across multiple perceptual and cognitive modalities, this visual-motor interaction might be expected to have a unified computational basis. Two essential tasks underlying such visual-motor cooperation are shown here to be simply expressed and directly solved as transformation-discovery inverse problems: (a) discriminating and determining the pose of a primed 3D object in a real-world scene, and (b) interpreting the 3D configuration of an articulated kinematic object in an image. The recently developed map-seeking method provides a mathematically tractable, cortically-plausible solution to these and a variety of other inverse problems which can be posed as the discovery of a composition of transformations between two patterns. The method relies on an ordering property of superpositions and on decomposition of the transformation spaces inherent in the generating processes of the problem.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
