<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:17+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Real-time adaptive information-theoretic optimization of neurophysiology experiments *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><surname>Lewi</surname></persName>
							<email>jlewi@gatech.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Bioengineering Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Columbia University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Butera</surname></persName>
							<email>rbutera@ece.gatech.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Bioengineering Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Columbia University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liam</forename><surname>Paninski</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Bioengineering Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">School of Electrical and Computer Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Columbia University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Real-time adaptive information-theoretic optimization of neurophysiology experiments *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Adaptively optimizing experiments can significantly reduce the number of trials needed to characterize neural responses using parametric statistical models. However , the potential for these methods has been limited to date by severe computational challenges: choosing the stimulus which will provide the most information about the (typically high-dimensional) model parameters requires evaluating a high-dimensional integration and optimization in near-real time. Here we present a fast algorithm for choosing the optimal (most informative) stimulus based on a Fisher approximation of the Shannon information and specialized numerical linear algebra techniques. This algorithm requires only low-rank matrix manipulations and a one-dimensional linesearch to choose the stimulus and is therefore efficient even for high-dimensional stimulus and parameter spaces; for example, we require just 15 milliseconds on a desktop computer to optimize a 100-dimensional stimulus. Our algorithm therefore makes real-time adaptive experimental design feasible. Simulation results show that model parameters can be estimated much more efficiently using these adaptive techniques than by using random (nonadap-tive) stimuli. Finally, we generalize the algorithm to efficiently handle both fast adaptation due to spike-history effects and slow, non-systematic drifts in the model parameters. Maximizing the efficiency of data collection is important in any experimental setting. In neuro-physiology experiments, minimizing the number of trials needed to characterize a neural system is essential for maintaining the viability of a preparation and ensuring robust results. As a result, various approaches have been developed to optimize neurophysiology experiments online in order to choose the &quot;best&quot; stimuli given prior knowledge of the system and the observed history of the cell&apos;s responses. The &quot;best&quot; stimulus can be defined a number of different ways depending on the experimental objectives. One reasonable choice, if we are interested in finding a neuron&apos;s &quot;preferred stimulus,&quot; is the stimulus which maximizes the firing rate of the neuron [1, 2, 3, 4]. Alternatively, when investigating the coding properties of sensory cells it makes sense to define the optimal stimulus in terms of the mutual information between the stimulus and response [5]. Here we take a system identification approach: we define the optimal stimulus as the one which tells us the most about how a neural system responds to its inputs [6, 7]. We consider neural systems in †</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
