<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Tradeoffs of Large Scale Learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Léon</forename><surname>Bottou</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">NEC laboratories of America Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Bousquet</surname></persName>
							<email>olivier.bousquet@m4x.org</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">NEC laboratories of America Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Google</forename><surname>Zürich</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">NEC laboratories of America Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Zurich</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">NEC laboratories of America Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><surname>Switzerland</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">NEC laboratories of America Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Tradeoffs of Large Scale Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This contribution develops a theoretical framework that takes into account the effect of approximate optimization on learning algorithms. The analysis shows distinct tradeoffs for the case of small-scale and large-scale learning problems. Small-scale learning problems are subject to the usual approximation-estimation tradeoff. Large-scale learning problems are subject to a qualitatively different tradeoff involving the computational complexity of the underlying optimization algorithms in non-trivial ways. 1 Motivation The computational complexity of learning algorithms has seldom been taken into account by the learning theory. Valiant [1] states that a problem is &quot;learnable&quot; when there exists a probably approx-imatively correct learning algorithm with polynomial complexity. Whereas much progress has been made on the statistical aspect (e.g., [2, 3, 4]), very little has been told about the complexity side of this proposal (e.g., [5].) Computational complexity becomes the limiting factor when one envisions large amounts of training data. Two important examples come to mind: • Data mining exists because competitive advantages can be achieved by analyzing the masses of data that describe the life of our computerized society. Since virtually every computer generates data, the data volume is proportional to the available computing power. Therefore one needs learning algorithms that scale roughly linearly with the total volume of data. • Artificial intelligence attempts to emulate the cognitive capabilities of human beings. Our biological brains can learn quite efficiently from the continuous streams of perceptual data generated by our six senses, using limited amounts of sugar as a source of power. This observation suggests that there are learning algorithms whose computing time requirements scale roughly linearly with the total volume of data. This contribution finds its source in the idea that approximate optimization algorithms might be sufficient for learning purposes. The first part proposes new decomposition of the test error where an additional term represents the impact of approximate optimization. In the case of small-scale learning problems, this decomposition reduces to the well known tradeoff between approximation error and estimation error. In the case of large-scale learning problems, the tradeoff is more complex because it involves the computational complexity of the learning algorithm. The second part explores the asymptotic properties of the large-scale learning tradeoff for various prototypical learning algorithms under various assumptions regarding the statistical estimation rates associated with the chosen objective functions. This part clearly shows that the best optimization algorithms are not necessarily the best learning algorithms. Maybe more surprisingly, certain algorithms perform well regardless of the assumed rate for the statistical estimation error.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
