<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Fast and Scalable Training of Semi-Supervised CRFs with Application to Activity Recognition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Maryam</forename><surname>Mahdaviani</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Tanzeem Choudhury</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of British Columbia Vancouver</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>BC</region>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Intel Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1100 NE 45th Street Seattle</addrLine>
									<postCode>98105</postCode>
									<region>WA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Fast and Scalable Training of Semi-Supervised CRFs with Application to Activity Recognition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a new and efficient semi-supervised training method for parameter estimation and feature selection in conditional random fields (CRFs). In real-world applications such as activity recognition, unlabeled sensor traces are relatively easy to obtain whereas labeled examples are expensive and tedious to collect. Furthermore, the ability to automatically select a small subset of discriminatory features from a large pool can be advantageous in terms of computational speed as well as accuracy. In this paper, we introduce the semi-supervised virtual evidence boosting (sVEB) algorithm for training CRFs-a semi-supervised extension to the recently developed virtual evidence boosting (VEB) method for feature selection and parameter learning. The objective function of sVEB combines the unlabeled conditional entropy with labeled conditional pseudo-likelihood. It reduces the overall system cost as well as the human labeling cost required during training, which are both important considerations in building real-world inference systems. Experiments on synthetic data and real activity traces collected from wearable sensors, illustrate that sVEB benefits from both the use of unlabeled data and automatic feature selection, and outperforms other semi-supervised approaches.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
