<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">HM-BiTAM: Bilingual Topic Exploration, Word Alignment, and Translation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bing</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
							<email>zhaob@us.ibm.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">IBM T. J. Watson Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Xing</surname></persName>
							<email>epxing@cs.cmu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">IBM T. J. Watson Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">HM-BiTAM: Bilingual Topic Exploration, Word Alignment, and Translation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a novel paradigm for statistical machine translation (SMT), based on a joint modeling of word alignment and the topical aspects underlying bilingual document-pairs, via a hidden Markov Bilingual Topic AdMixture (HM-BiTAM). In this paradigm, parallel sentence-pairs from a parallel document-pair are coupled via a certain semantic-flow, to ensure coherence of topical context in the alignment of mapping words between languages, likelihood-based training of topic-dependent translational lexicons, as well as in the inference of topic representations in each language. The learned HM-BiTAM can not only display topic patterns like methods such as LDA [1], but now for bilingual corpora; it also offers a principled way of inferring optimal translation using document context. Our method integrates the conventional model of HMM-a key component for most of the state-of-the-art SMT systems, with the recently proposed BiTAM model [10]; we report an extensive empirical analysis (in many ways complementary to the description-oriented [10]) of our method in three aspects: bilingual topic representation, word alignment, and translation.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
