<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Joint support recovery under high-dimensional scaling: Benefits and perils of 񮽙 1,∞-regularization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Sahand</forename><surname>Negahban</surname></persName>
							<email>sahand n@eecs.berkeley.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Statistics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720-1770</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Martin</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wainwright</surname></persName>
							<email>wainwrig@eecs.berkeley.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of California</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720-1770</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Joint support recovery under high-dimensional scaling: Benefits and perils of 񮽙 1,∞-regularization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Given a collection of r ≥ 2 linear regression problems in p dimensions, suppose that the regression coefficients share partially common supports. This setup suggests the use of 񮽙 1 // ∞-regularized regression for joint estimation of the p × r matrix of regression coefficients. We analyze the high-dimensional scaling of 񮽙 1 // ∞-regularized quadratic programming , considering both consistency rates in 񮽙 ∞-norm, and also how the minimal sample size n required for performing variable selection grows as a function of the model dimension, sparsity, and overlap between the supports. We begin by establishing bounds on the 񮽙 ∞-error as well sufficient conditions for exact variable selection for fixed design matrices, as well as designs drawn randomly from general Gaussian matrices. These results show that the high-dimensional scaling of 񮽙 1 // ∞-regularization is qualitatively similar to that of ordinary 񮽙 1-regularization. Our second set of results applies to design matrices drawn from standard Gaussian ensembles, for which we provide a sharp set of necessary and sufficient conditions: the 񮽙 1 // ∞-regularized method undergoes a phase transition characterized by the rescaled sample size θ 1,∞ (n, p, s, α) = n/{(4 − 3α)s log(p − (2 − α) s)}. More precisely, for any δ &gt; 0, the probability of successfully recovering both supports converges to 1 for scalings such that θ 1,∞ ≥ 1 + δ, and converges to 0 for scalings for which θ 1,∞ ≤ 1 − δ. An implication of this threshold is that use of 񮽙 1,∞-regularization yields improved statistical efficiency if the overlap parameter is large enough (α &gt; 2/3), but performs worse than a naive Lasso-based approach for moderate to small overlap (α &lt; 2/3). We illustrate the close agreement between these theoretical predictions, and the actual behavior in simulations.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
