<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Natural Image Denoising with Convolutional Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Viren</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Brain &amp; Cognitive Sciences Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">Sebastian</forename><surname>Seung</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Brain &amp; Cognitive Sciences Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Howard Hughes Medical Institute Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Natural Image Denoising with Convolutional Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present an approach to low-level vision that combines two main ideas: the use of convolutional networks as an image processing architecture and an unsu-pervised learning procedure that synthesizes training samples from specific noise models. We demonstrate this approach on the challenging problem of natural image denoising. Using a test set with a hundred natural images, we find that con-volutional networks provide comparable and in some cases superior performance to state of the art wavelet and Markov random field (MRF) methods. Moreover, we find that a convolutional network offers similar performance in the blind de-noising setting as compared to other techniques in the non-blind setting. We also show how convolutional networks are mathematically related to MRF approaches by presenting a mean field theory for an MRF specially designed for image denois-ing. Although these approaches are related, convolutional networks avoid computational difficulties in MRF approaches that arise from probabilistic learning and inference. This makes it possible to learn image processing architectures that have a high degree of representational power (we train models with over 15,000 parameters), but whose computational expense is significantly less than that associated with inference in MRF approaches with even hundreds of parameters. 1 Background Low-level image processing tasks include edge detection, interpolation, and deconvolution. These tasks are useful both in themselves, and as a front-end for high-level visual tasks like object recognition. This paper focuses on the task of denoising, defined as the recovery of an underlying image from an observation that has been subjected to Gaussian noise. One approach to image denoising is to transform an image from pixel intensities into another representation where statistical regularities are more easily captured. For example, the Gaussian scale mixture (GSM) model introduced by Portilla and colleagues is based on a multiscale wavelet decomposition that provides an effective description of local image statistics [1, 2]. Another approach is to try and capture statistical regularities of pixel intensities directly using Markov random fields (MRFs) to define a prior over the image space. Initial work used hand-designed settings of the parameters, but recently there has been increasing success in learning the parameters of such models from databases of natural images [3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8]. Prior models can be used for tasks such as image denoising by augmenting the prior with a noise model. Alternatively, an MRF can be used to model the probability distribution of the clean image conditioned on the noisy image. This conditional random field (CRF) approach is said to be discrimi-native, in contrast to the generative MRF approach. Several researchers have shown that the CRF approach can outperform generative learning on various image restoration and labeling tasks [9, 10]. CRFs have recently been applied to the problem of image denoising as well [5].</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
