<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning to use Working Memory in Partially Observable Environments through Dopaminergic Reinforcement</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Todd</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology &amp; Princeton</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Neuroscience Institute Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yael</forename><surname>Niv</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology &amp; Princeton</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Neuroscience Institute Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology &amp; Princeton</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Neuroscience Institute Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning to use Working Memory in Partially Observable Environments through Dopaminergic Reinforcement</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Working memory is a central topic of cognitive neuroscience because it is critical for solving real-world problems in which information from multiple temporally distant sources must be combined to generate appropriate behavior. However, an often neglected fact is that learning to use working memory effectively is itself a difficult problem. The Gating framework [1-4] is a collection of psychological models that show how dopamine can train the basal ganglia and prefrontal cortex to form useful working memory representations in certain types of problems. We unite Gating with machine learning theory concerning the general problem of memory-based optimal control [5-6]. We present a normative model that learns, by online temporal difference methods, to use working memory to maximize discounted future reward in partially observable settings. The model successfully solves a benchmark working memory problem, and exhibits limitations similar to those observed in humans. Our purpose is to introduce a concise, normative definition of high level cognitive concepts such as working memory and cognitive control in terms of maximizing discounted future rewards. 1 Introduction Working memory is loosely defined in cognitive neuroscience as information that is (1) internally maintained on a temporary or short term basis, and (2) required for tasks in which immediate observations cannot be mapped to correct actions. It is widely assumed that prefrontal cortex (PFC) plays a role in maintaining and updating working memory. However, relatively little is known about how PFC develops useful working memory representations for a new task. Furthermore, current work focuses on describing the structure and limitations of working memory, but does not ask why, or in what general class of tasks, is it necessary. Borrowing from the theory of optimal control in partially observable Markov decision problems (POMDPs), we frame the psychological concept of working memory as an internal state representation, developed and employed to maximize future reward in partially observable environments. We combine computational insights from POMDPs and neurobiologically plausible models from cognitive neuroscience to suggest a simple reinforcement learning (RL) model of working memory function that can be implemented through dopaminergic training of the basal ganglia and PFC. The Gating framework is a series of cognitive neuroscience models developed to explain how dopaminergic RL signals can shape useful working memory representations [1-4]. Computationally this framework models working memory as a collection of past observations, each of which can occasionally be replaced with the current observation, and addresses the problem of learning when to update each memory element versus maintaining it. In the original Gating model [1-2] the PFC contained a unitary working memory</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
