<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Signal-to-Noise Ratio Analysis of Policy Gradient Algorithms</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Russ</forename><surname>Tedrake</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artificial Intelligence Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02139</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Signal-to-Noise Ratio Analysis of Policy Gradient Algorithms</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Policy gradient (PG) reinforcement learning algorithms have strong (local) convergence guarantees, but their learning performance is typically limited by a large variance in the estimate of the gradient. In this paper, we formulate the variance reduction problem by describing a signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) for policy gradient algorithms, and evaluate this SNR carefully for the popular Weight Perturbation (WP) algorithm. We confirm that SNR is a good predictor of long-term learning performance, and that in our episodic formulation, the cost-to-go function is indeed the optimal baseline. We then propose two modifications to traditional model-free policy gradient algorithms in order to optimize the SNR. First, we examine WP using anisotropic sampling distributions, which introduces a bias into the update but increases the SNR; this bias can be interpreted as following the natural gradient of the cost function. Second, we show that non-Gaussian distributions can also increase the SNR, and argue that the optimal isotropic distribution is a &apos;shell&apos; distribution with a constant magnitude and uniform distribution in direction. We demonstrate that both modifications produce substantial improvements in learning performance in challenging policy gradient experiments.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
