<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:18+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Goal-directed decision making in prefrontal cortex: A computational framework</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Botvinick</surname></persName>
							<email>matthewb@princeton.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Princeton Neuroscience Institute and Computer Science Department Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Princeton University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Princeton University Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540, 08540</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ, NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>An</surname></persName>
							<email>an@princeton.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Princeton Neuroscience Institute and Computer Science Department Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Princeton University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Princeton University Princeton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08540, 08540</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ, NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Goal-directed decision making in prefrontal cortex: A computational framework</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Research in animal learning and behavioral neuroscience has distinguished between two forms of action control: a habit-based form, which relies on stored action values, and a goal-directed form, which forecasts and compares action outcomes based on a model of the environment. While habit-based control has been the subject of extensive computational research, the computational principles underlying goal-directed control in animals have so far received less attention. In the present paper, we advance a computational framework for goal-directed control in animals and humans. We take three empirically motivated points as founding premises: (1) Neurons in dorsolateral prefrontal cortex represent action policies, (2) Neurons in orbitofrontal cortex represent rewards, and (3) Neural computation, across domains, can be appropriately understood as performing structured probabilistic inference. On a purely computational level, the resulting account relates closely to previous work using Bayesian inference to solve Markov decision problems, but extends this work by introducing a new algorithm, which provably converges on optimal plans. On a cognitive and neuroscientific level, the theory provides a unifying framework for several different forms of goal-directed action selection, placing emphasis on a novel form, within which orbitofrontal reward representations directly drive policy selection. 1 Goal-directed action control In the study of human and animal behavior, it is a long-standing idea that reward-based decision making may rely on two qualitatively different mechanisms. In habit-based decision making, stimuli elicit reflex-like responses, shaped by past reinforcement [1]. In goal-directed or purposive decision making, on the other hand, actions are selected based on a prospective consideration of possible outcomes and future lines of action [2]. Over the past twenty years or so, the attention of cognitive neuroscientists and computationally minded psychologists has tended to focus on habit-based control, due in large part to interest in potential links between dopaminergic function and temporal-difference algorithms for reinforcement learning. However, a resurgence of interest in purposive action selection is now being driven by innovations in animal behavior research, which have yielded powerful new behavioral assays [3], and revealed specific effects of focal neural damage on goal-directed behavior [4]. In discussing some of the relevant data, Daw, Niv and Dayan [5] recently pointed out the close relationship between purposive decision making, as understood in the behavioral sciences, and model-based methods for the solution of Markov decision problems (MDPs), where action policies are derived from a joint analysis of a transition function (a mapping</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
