<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Multi-Stage Dantzig Selector</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ji</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Arizona State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Wonka</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Arizona State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jieping</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Arizona State University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Multi-Stage Dantzig Selector</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We consider the following sparse signal recovery (or feature selection) problem: given a design matrix X ∈ R n×m (m n) and a noisy observation vector y ∈ R n satisfying y = Xβ * + where is the noise vector following a Gaussian distribution N (0, σ 2 I), how to recover the signal (or parameter vector) β * when the signal is sparse? The Dantzig selector has been proposed for sparse signal recovery with strong theoretical guarantees. In this paper, we propose a multi-stage Dantzig selector method, which iteratively refines the target signal β *. We show that if X obeys a certain condition, then with a large probability the difference between the solutionˆβ solutionˆ solutionˆβ estimated by the proposed method and the true solution β * measured in terms of the l p norm (p ≥ 1) is bounded asˆβ asˆ asˆβ − β * p ≤ C(s − N) 1/p log m + ∆ σ, where C is a constant, s is the number of nonzero entries in β * , ∆ is independent of m and is much smaller than the first term, and N is the number of entries of β * larger than a certain value in the order of O(σ √ log m). The proposed method improves the estimation bound of the standard Dantzig selector approximately from Cs 1/p √ log mσ to C(s − N) 1/p √ log mσ where the value N depends on the number of large entries in β *. When N = s, the proposed algorithm achieves the oracle solution with a high probability. In addition, with a large probability, the proposed method can select the same number of correct features under a milder condition than the Dantzig selector.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
