<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning from Candidate Labeling Sets</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Luo</forename><surname>Jie</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DSI, Università degli Studi di Milano</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Idiap Research Institute and EPF Lausanne</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Francesco</forename><surname>Orabona</surname></persName>
							<email>orabona@dsi.unimi.it</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">DSI, Università degli Studi di Milano</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Idiap Research Institute and EPF Lausanne</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning from Candidate Labeling Sets</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In many real world applications we do not have access to fully-labeled training data, but only to a list of possible labels. This is the case, e.g., when learning visual classifiers from images downloaded from the web, using just their text captions or tags as learning oracles. In general, these problems can be very difficult. However most of the time there exist different implicit sources of information, coming from the relations between instances and labels, which are usually dismissed. In this paper, we propose a semi-supervised framework to model this kind of problems. Each training sample is a bag containing multi-instances, associated with a set of candidate labeling vectors. Each labeling vector encodes the possible labels for the instances in the bag, with only one being fully correct. The use of the labeling vectors provides a principled way not to exclude any information. We propose a large margin discriminative formulation, and an efficient algorithm to solve it. Experiments conducted on artificial datasets and a real-world images and captions dataset show that our approach achieves performance comparable to an SVM trained with the ground-truth labels, and outperforms other baselines.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
