<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Inferring Stimulus Selectivity from the Spatial Structure of Neural Network Dynamics</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kanaka</forename><surname>Rajan</surname></persName>
							<email>krajan@princeton.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Abbott</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Haim</forename><surname>Sompolinsky</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Lewis-Sigler Institute for Integrative Genomics Carl Icahn Laboratories # 262</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Neuroscience Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">of Physiology and Cellular Biophysics Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons New York</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Princeton University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08544, 10032-2695</postCode>
									<settlement>Princeton</settlement>
									<region>NJ, NY</region>
									<country>USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Israel and Center for Brain Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Racah Institute of Physics Interdisciplinary Center for Neural Computation Hebrew University Jerusalem</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Harvard University Cambridge</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>02138</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Inferring Stimulus Selectivity from the Spatial Structure of Neural Network Dynamics</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>How are the spatial patterns of spontaneous and evoked population responses re-lated? We study the impact of connectivity on the spatial pattern of fluctuations in the input-generated response, by comparing the distribution of evoked and in-trinsically generated activity across the different units of a neural network. We develop a complementary approach to principal component analysis in which separate high-variance directions are derived for each input condition. We analyze subspace angles to compute the difference between the shapes of trajectories corresponding to different network states, and the orientation of the low-dimensional subspaces that driven trajectories occupy within the full space of neuronal activity. In addition to revealing how the spatiotemporal structure of spontaneous activity affects input-evoked responses, these methods can be used to infer input selec-tivity induced by network dynamics from experimentally accessible measures of spontaneous activity (e.g. from voltage-or calcium-sensitive optical imaging experiments). We conclude that the absence of a detailed spatial map of afferent inputs and cortical connectivity does not limit our ability to design spatially extended stimuli that evoke strong responses.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
