<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian Framework for Figure-Ground Interpretation</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vicky</forename><surname>Froyen</surname></persName>
							<email>vicky.froyen@eden.rutgers.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Center for Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory of Experimental Psychology University of Leuven (K.U. Leuven)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Cognitive Science Rutgers University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08854</postCode>
									<settlement>Piscataway</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Cognitive Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rutgers University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08854</postCode>
									<settlement>Piscataway</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Manish</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
							<email>manish@ruccs.rutgers.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Rutgers University</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08854</postCode>
									<settlement>Piscataway</settlement>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Bayesian Framework for Figure-Ground Interpretation</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Figure/ground assignment, in which the visual image is divided into nearer (figu-ral) and farther (ground) surfaces, is an essential step in visual processing, but its underlying computational mechanisms are poorly understood. Figural assignment (often referred to as border ownership) can vary along a contour, suggesting a spatially distributed process whereby local and global cues are combined to yield local estimates of border ownership. In this paper we model figure/ground estimation in a Bayesian belief network, attempting to capture the propagation of border ownership across the image as local cues (contour curvature and T-junctions) interact with more global cues to yield a figure/ground assignment. Our network includes as a nonlocal factor skeletal (medial axis) structure, under the hypothesis that medial structure &quot;draws&quot; border ownership so that borders are owned by the skeletal hypothesis that best explains them. We also briefly present a psychophys-ical experiment in which we measured local border ownership along a contour at various distances from an inducing cue (a T-junction). Both the human subjects and the network show similar patterns of performance, converging rapidly to a similar pattern of spatial variation in border ownership along contours. Figure/ground assignment (further referred to as f/g), in which the visual image is divided into nearer (figural) and farther (ground) surfaces, is an essential step in visual processing. A number of factors are known to affect f/g assignment, including region size [9], convexity [7, 16], and symmetry [1, 7, 11]. Figural assignment (often referred to as border ownership, under the assumption that the figural side &quot;owns&quot; the border) is usually studied globally, meaning that entire surfaces and their enclosing boundaries are assumed to receive a globally consistent figural status. But recent psy-chophysical findings [8] have suggested that border ownership can vary locally along a boundary, even leading to a globally inconsistent figure/ground assignment-broadly consistent with electro-physiological evidence showing local coding for border ownership in area V2 as early as 68 msec after image onset [20]. This suggests a spatially distributed and potentially competitive process of figural assignment [15], in which adjacent surfaces compete to own their common boundary, with figural status propagating across the image as this competition proceeds. But both the principles and computational mechanisms underlying this process are poorly understood.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
