<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Online Learning in the Manifold of Low-Rank Matrices</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uri</forename><surname>Shalit</surname></persName>
							<email>uri.shalit@mail.huji.ac.il</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Dept. and ICNC</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Google Research and The Gonda Brain Research Center Bar Ilan University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Hebrew University of Jerusalem</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Daphna</forename><surname>Weinshall</surname></persName>
							<email>daphna@cs.huji.ac.il</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Dept. and ICNC</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Google Research and The Gonda Brain Research Center Bar Ilan University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Hebrew University of Jerusalem</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Gal</forename><surname>Chechik</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Dept. and ICNC</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Google Research and The Gonda Brain Research Center Bar Ilan University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Hebrew University of Jerusalem</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Online Learning in the Manifold of Low-Rank Matrices</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>When learning models that are represented in matrix forms, enforcing a low-rank constraint can dramatically improve the memory and run time complexity, while providing a natural regularization of the model. However, naive approaches for minimizing functions over the set of low-rank matrices are either prohibitively time consuming (repeated singular value decomposition of the matrix) or numerically unstable (optimizing a factored representation of the low rank matrix). We build on recent advances in optimization over manifolds, and describe an iterative online learning procedure, consisting of a gradient step, followed by a second-order retraction back to the manifold. While the ideal retraction is hard to compute, and so is the projection operator that approximates it, we describe another second-order retraction that can be computed efficiently, with run time and memory complexity of O ((n + m)k) for a rank-k matrix of dimension m × n, given rank-one gradients. We use this algorithm, LORETA, to learn a matrix-form similarity measure over pairs of documents represented as high dimensional vectors. LORETA improves the mean average precision over a passive-aggressive approach in a factorized model, and also improves over a full model trained over pre-selected features using the same memory requirements. LORETA also showed consistent improvement over standard methods in a large (1600 classes) multi-label image classification task.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
