<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:20+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Short-Term Memory Architecture for the Learning of Morphophonemic Rules</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Gasser</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indiana University Bloomington</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>47405</postCode>
									<region>IN</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chan-Do</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Indiana University Bloomington</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>47405</postCode>
									<region>IN</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Short-Term Memory Architecture for the Learning of Morphophonemic Rules</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Despite its successes, Rumelhart and McClelland&apos;s (1986) well-known approach to the learning of morphophonemic rules suffers from two deficiencies: (1) It performs the artificial task of associating forms with forms rather than perception or production. (2) It is not constrained in ways that humans learners are. This paper describes a model which addresses both objections. Using a simple recurrent architecture which takes both forms and &quot;meanings&quot; as inputs, the model learns to generate verbs in one or another &quot;tense&quot;, given arbitrary meanings, and to recognize the tenses of verbs. Furthermore, it fails to learn reversal processes unknown in human language. 1 BACKGROUND In the debate over the power of connectionist models to handle linguistic phenomena , considerable attention has been focused on the learning of simple morphological rules. It is a straightforward matter in a symbolic system to specify how the meanings of a stem and a bound morpheme combine to yield the meaning of a whole word and how the form of the bound morpheme depends on the shape of the stem. In a distributed connectionist system, however, where there may be no explicit morphemes, words, or rules, things are not so simple. The most important work in this area has been that of Rumelhart and McClelland (1986), together with later extensions by Marchman and Plunkett (1989). The networks involved were trained to associate English verb stems with the corresponding past-tense forms, successfully generating both regular and irregular forms and generalizing to novel inputs. This work established that rule-like linguistic behavior 605</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
