<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:21+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">From Stochastic Nonlinear Integrate-and-Fire to Generalized Linear Models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Skander</forename><surname>Mensi</surname></persName>
							<email>skander.mensi@epfl.ch</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Naud</surname></persName>
							<email>richard.naud@epfl.ch</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wulfram</forename><surname>Gersnter</surname></persName>
							<email>wulfram.gerstner@epfl.ch</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer and Communication Sciences and Brain-Mind Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">School of Computer and Communication Sciences and Brain-Mind Institute Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne 1015 Lausanne EPFL</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1015 Lausanne EPFL</addrLine>
									<country>SWITZERLAND, SWITZERLAND</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">School of Computer and Communication Sciences and Brain-Mind Institute Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne 1015 Lausanne EPFL</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CH">SWITZERLAND</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">From Stochastic Nonlinear Integrate-and-Fire to Generalized Linear Models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Variability in single neuron models is typically implemented either by a stochastic Leaky-Integrate-and-Fire model or by a model of the Generalized Linear Model (GLM) family. We use analytical and numerical methods to relate state-of-the-art models from both schools of thought. First we find the analytical expressions relating the subthreshold voltage from the Adaptive Exponential Integrate-and-Fire model (AdEx) to the Spike-Response Model with escape noise (SRM as an example of a GLM). Then we calculate numerically the link-function that provides the firing probability given a deterministic membrane potential. We find a mathematical expression for this link-function and test the ability of the GLM to predict the firing probability of a neuron receiving complex stimulation. Comparing the prediction performance of various link-functions, we find that a GLM with an exponential link-function provides an excellent approximation to the Adaptive Exponential Integrate-and-Fire with colored-noise input. These results help to understand the relationship between the different approaches to stochastic neuron models. 1 Motivation When it comes to modeling the intrinsic variability in simple neuron models, we can distinguish two traditional approaches. One approach is inspired by the stochastic Leaky Integrate-and-Fire (LIF) hypothesis of Stein (1967) [1], where a noise term is added to the system of differential equations implementing the leaky integration to a threshold. There are multiple versions of such a stochastic LIF [2]. How the noise affects the firing probability is also a function of the parameters of the neuron model. Therefore, it is important to take into account the refinements of simple neuron models in terms of subthreshold resonance [3, 4], spike-triggered adaptation [5, 6] and non-linear spike 1</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
