<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:21+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Global Structural EM Algorithm for a Model of Cancer Progression</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Tofigh</surname></persName>
							<email>ali.tofigh@mcgill.ca</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Sjölund</surname></persName>
							<email>erik.sjölund@sbc.su.se</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mattias</forename><surname>Höglund</surname></persName>
							<email>mattias.hoglund@med.lu.se</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jens</forename><surname>Lagergren</surname></persName>
							<email>jensl@csc.kth.se</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">School of Computer Science McGill Centre for Bioinformatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Stockholm Bioinformatics Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">McGill University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Oncology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stockholm University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SE">Sweden</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Science for Life Lab Swedish e-Science Research Center Stockholm Bioinformatics Center School of Computer Science and Communication KTH Royal Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Lund University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>Sweden, Sweden</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Global Structural EM Algorithm for a Model of Cancer Progression</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Cancer has complex patterns of progression that include converging as well as diverging progressional pathways. Vogelstein&apos;s path model of colon cancer was a pioneering contribution to cancer research. Since then, several attempts have been made at obtaining mathematical models of cancer progression, devising learning algorithms, and applying these to cross-sectional data. Beerenwinkel et al. provided , what they coined, EM-like algorithms for Oncogenetic Trees (OTs) and mixtures of such. Given the small size of current and future data sets, it is important to minimize the number of parameters of a model. For this reason, we too focus on tree-based models and introduce Hidden-variable Oncogenetic Trees (HOTs). In contrast to OTs, HOTs allow for errors in the data and thereby provide more realistic modeling. We also design global structural EM algorithms for learning HOTs and mixtures of HOTs (HOT-mixtures). The algorithms are global in the sense that, during the M-step, they find a structure that yields a global maximum of the expected complete log-likelihood rather than merely one that improves it. The algorithm for single HOTs performs very well on reasonable-sized data sets, while that for HOT-mixtures requires data sets of sizes obtainable only with tomorrow&apos;s more cost-efficient technologies.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
