<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:21+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Generalized Lasso based Approximation of Sparse Coding for Visual Recognition</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Nobuyuki</forename><surname>Morioka</surname></persName>
							<email>nmorioka@cse.unsw.edu.au</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">The University of New South Wales &amp; NICTA Sydney</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shin</forename><forename type="middle">&amp;apos;</forename><surname>Ichi Satoh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">National Institute of Informatics</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="JP">Japan</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Generalized Lasso based Approximation of Sparse Coding for Visual Recognition</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Sparse coding, a method of explaining sensory data with as few dictionary bases as possible, has attracted much attention in computer vision. For visual object category recognition, 1 regularized sparse coding is combined with the spatial pyramid representation to obtain state-of-the-art performance. However, because of its iterative optimization, applying sparse coding onto every local feature descriptor extracted from an image database can become a major bottleneck. To overcome this computational challenge, this paper presents &quot;Generalized Lasso based Approximation of Sparse coding&quot; (GLAS). By representing the distribution of sparse coefficients with slice transform, we fit a piece-wise linear mapping function with the generalized lasso. We also propose an efficient post-refinement procedure to perform mutual inhibition between bases which is essential for an overcomplete setting. The experiments show that GLAS obtains a comparable performance to 1 regularized sparse coding, yet achieves a significant speed up demonstrating its effectiveness for large-scale visual recognition problems.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
