<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:21+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Action Content On-Line and in Real Time before Action Onset-an Intracranial Human Study</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Uri</forename><surname>Maoz</surname></persName>
							<email>urim@caltech.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Shengxuan</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
							<email>ianrossmd@aol.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Mamelak</surname></persName>
							<email>adam.mamelak@cshs.org</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Christof</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
							<email>koch@klab.caltech.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Huntington Hospital Pasadena</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Los Angeles</settlement>
									<region>CA, CA, CA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Allen Institute for Brain Science Seattle</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>CA, WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Action Content On-Line and in Real Time before Action Onset-an Intracranial Human Study</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The ability to predict action content from neural signals in real time before the action occurs has been long sought in the neuroscientific study of decision-making, agency and volition. On-line real-time (ORT) prediction is important for understanding the relation between neural correlates of decision-making and conscious, voluntary action as well as for brain-machine interfaces. Here, epilepsy patients, implanted with intracranial depth microelectrodes or subdural grid electrodes for clinical purposes, participated in a &quot;matching-pennies&quot; game against an opponent. In each trial, subjects were given a 5 s countdown, after which they had to raise their left or right hand immediately as the &quot;go&quot; signal appeared on a computer screen. They won a fixed amount of money if they raised a different hand than their opponent and lost that amount otherwise. The question we here studied was the extent to which neural precursors of the subjects&apos; decisions can be detected in intracranial local field potentials (LFP) prior to the onset of the action. We found that combined low-frequency (0.1-5 Hz) LFP signals from 10 electrodes were predictive of the intended left-/right-hand movements before the onset of the go signal. Our ORT system predicted which hand the patient would raise 0.5 s before the go signal with 68±3% accuracy in two patients. Based on these results, we constructed an ORT system that tracked up to 30 electrodes simultaneously, and tested it on retrospective data from 7 patients. On average, we could predict the correct hand choice in 83% of the trials, which rose to 92% if we let the system drop 3/10 of the trials on which it was less confident. Our system demonstrates-for the first time-the feasibility of accurately predicting a binary action on single trials in real time for patients with intracranial recordings, well before the action occurs.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
