<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:22+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A comparison between a neural network model for the formation of brain maps and experimental data</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Obermayer</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Harvard Medical School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Beckman-Institute University of Illinois Urbana</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Beckman-Institute University of Illinois Urbana</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Harvard University Boston</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>61801, 61801, 02115</postCode>
									<region>IL, IL, MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schulten</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Harvard Medical School</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Beckman-Institute University of Illinois Urbana</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Beckman-Institute University of Illinois Urbana</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">Harvard University Boston</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>61801, 61801, 02115</postCode>
									<region>IL, IL, MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A comparison between a neural network model for the formation of brain maps and experimental data</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>G.G. Blasdel Recently, high resolution images of the simultaneous representation of orientation preference, orientation selectivity and ocular dominance have been obtained for large areas in monkey striate cortex by optical imaging [1-3]. These data allow for the first time a &quot;local&quot; as well as &quot;global&quot; description of the spatial patterns and provide strong evidence for correlations between orientation selectivity and ocular dominance. A quantitative analysis reveals that these correlations arise when a five-dimensional feature space (two dimensions for retinotopic space, one each for orientation preference, orientation specificity, and ocular dominance) is mapped into the two available dimensions of cortex while locally preserving topology. These results provide strong evidence for the concept of topology preserving maps which have been suggested as a basic design principle of striate cortex [4-7]. Monkey striate cortex contains a retinotopic map in which are embedded the highly repetitive patterns of orientation selectivity and ocular dominance. The retinotopic projection establishes a &quot;global&quot; order, while maps of variables describing other stimulus features, in particular line orientation and ocularity, dominate cortical organization locally. A large number of pattern models [8-12] as well as models of development [6,7,13-21] have been proposed to describe the spatial structure of these patterns and their development during ontogenesis. However, most models have not been compared with experimental data in detail. There are two reasons for this: (i) many model-studies were not elaborated enough to be experimentally testable and (ii) a sufficient amount of experimental data obtained from large areas of striate cortex was not available. 83</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
