<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:22+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The VC-Dimension versus the Statistical Capacity of Multilayer Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Chuanyi</forename><surname>Ji</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91125</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Demetri</forename><surname>Psaltis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91125</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The VC-Dimension versus the Statistical Capacity of Multilayer Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A general relationship is developed between the VC-dimension and the statistical lower epsilon-capacity which shows that the VC-dimension can be lower bounded (in order) by the statistical lower epsilon-capacity of a network trained with random samples. This relationship explains quantitatively how generalization takes place after memorization, and relates the concept of generalization (consistency) with the capacity of the optimal classifier over a class of classifiers with the same structure and the capacity of the Bayesian classifier. Furthermore, it provides a general methodology to evaluate a lower bound for the VC-dimension of feedforward multilayer neural networks. This general methodology is applied to two types of networks which are important for hardware implementations: two layer (N-2L-1) networks with binary weights, integer thresholds for the hidden units and zero threshold for the output unit, and a single neuron ((N-1) networks) with binary weigths and a zero threshold. Specifically, we obtain OC~L) ::; d2 ::; O(W), and d1 &quot;&quot;&apos; O(N). Here W is the total number of weights of the (N-2L-1) networks. d1 and d 2 represent the VC-dimensions for the (N-1) and (N-2L-1) networks respectively.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
