<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:22+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A new metric on the manifold of kernel matrices with application to matrix geometric means</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suvrit</forename><surname>Sra</surname></persName>
							<email>suvrit@tuebingen.mpg.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Max Planck Institute for Intelligent Systems</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>72076</postCode>
									<settlement>Tübigen</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A new metric on the manifold of kernel matrices with application to matrix geometric means</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Symmetric positive definite (spd) matrices pervade numerous scientific disciplines , including machine learning and optimization. We consider the key task of measuring distances between two spd matrices; a task that is often nontriv-ial whenever the distance function must respect the non-Euclidean geometry of spd matrices. Typical non-Euclidean distance measures such as the Riemannian metric δ R (X, Y) = log(Y −1/2 XY −1/2) F , are computationally demanding and also complicated to use. To allay some of these difficulties, we introduce a new metric on spd matrices, which not only respects non-Euclidean geometry but also offers faster computation than δ R while being less complicated to use. We support our claims theoretically by listing a set of theorems that relate our metric to δ R (X, Y), and experimentally by studying the nonconvex problem of computing matrix geometric means based on squared distances.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
