<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:22+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">AN ADAPTIVE AND HETERODYNE FILTERING PROCEDURE FOR THE IMAGING OF MOVING OBJECTS A FEW REMARKS ON THE FLY VISUAL SYSTEM</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Schuling</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Biophysics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory for General Physics Westersingel 34</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9718 eM</postCode>
									<settlement>Groningen</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A K</forename><surname>Mastebroek</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Biophysics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory for General Physics Westersingel 34</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9718 eM</postCode>
									<settlement>Groningen</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Zaagman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Biophysics Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory for General Physics Westersingel 34</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>9718 eM</postCode>
									<settlement>Groningen</settlement>
									<country key="NL">The Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">AN ADAPTIVE AND HETERODYNE FILTERING PROCEDURE FOR THE IMAGING OF MOVING OBJECTS A FEW REMARKS ON THE FLY VISUAL SYSTEM</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>662</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Recent experimental work on the stimulus velocity dependent time resolving power of the neural units, situated in the highest order optic ganglion of the blowfly, revealed the at first sight amazing phenomenon that at this high level of the fly visual system, the time constants of these units which are involved in the processing of neural activity evoked by moving objects, are-roughly spoken-inverse proportional to the velocity of those objects over an extremely wide range. In this paper we will discuss the implementation of a two dimensional heterodyne adaptive filter construction into a computer simulation model. The features of this simulation model include the ability to account for the experimentally observed stimulus-tuned adaptive temporal behaviour of time constants in the fly visual system. The simulation results obtained, clearly show that the application of such an adaptive processing procedure delivers an improved imaging technique of moving patterns in the high velocity range. The visual system of the diptera, including the blowfly Calliphora erythrocephala (Mg.) is very regularly organized and allows therefore very precise optical stimulation techniques. Also, long term electrophysiological recordings can be made relatively easy in this visual system, For these reasons the blowfly (which is well-known as a very rapid and &apos;clever&apos; pilot) turns out to be an extremely suitable animal for a systematic study of basic principles that may underlie the detection and further processing of movement information at the neural level. In the fly visual system the input retinal mosaic structure is precisely mapped onto the higher order optic ganglia (lamina, medulla, lobula), This means that each neural column in each ganglion in this visual system corresponds to a certain optical axis in the visual field of the compound eye. In the lobula complex a set of wide-field movement sensitive neurons is found, each of which integrates the input signals over the whole visual field of the entire eye, One of these wide field neurons, that has been classified as H I by Hausen J has been extensively studied both anatomically2, 3, 4 as well as electrophysiologically5, 6, 7, The obtained results generally agree very well with those found in behavioral optomotor experiments on movement detection 8 and can be understood in terms of Reichardts correlation model 9 , 10. The H I neuron is sensitive to horizontal movement and directionally selective: very high rates of action potentials (spikes) up to 300 per second can be recorded from this element in the case of visual stimuli which move horizontally inward, i.e. from back to front in the visual field (pre/erred direction), whereas movement horizontally outward, i.e, from front to back (null direction) suppresses its activity,</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
