<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Recurrent networks of coupled Winner-Take-All oscillators for solving constraint satisfaction problems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Hesham</forename><surname>Mostafa</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Neuroinformatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich and ETH Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lorenz</forename><forename type="middle">K M</forename></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Neuroinformatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich and ETH Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Giacomo</forename><surname>Indiveri</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute for Neuroinformatics</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Zurich and ETH Zurich</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Recurrent networks of coupled Winner-Take-All oscillators for solving constraint satisfaction problems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a recurrent neuronal network, modeled as a continuous-time dynami-cal system, that can solve constraint satisfaction problems. Discrete variables are represented by coupled Winner-Take-All (WTA) networks, and their values are encoded in localized patterns of oscillations that are learned by the recurrent weights in these networks. Constraints over the variables are encoded in the network con-nectivity. Although there are no sources of noise, the network can escape from local optima in its search for solutions that satisfy all constraints by modifying the effective network connectivity through oscillations. If there is no solution that satisfies all constraints, the network state changes in a seemingly random manner and its trajectory approximates a sampling procedure that selects a variable assignment with a probability that increases with the fraction of constraints satisfied by this assignment. External evidence, or input to the network, can force variables to specific values. When new inputs are applied, the network re-evaluates the entire set of variables in its search for states that satisfy the maximum number of constraints , while being consistent with the external input. Our results demonstrate that the proposed network architecture can perform a deterministic search for the optimal solution to problems with non-convex cost functions. The network is inspired by canonical microcircuit models of the cortex and suggests possible dy-namical mechanisms to solve constraint satisfaction problems that can be present in biological networks, or implemented in neuromorphic electronic circuits.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
