<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Dynamically-Adaptive Winner-Take-All Networks</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Laale</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Artif1cia1IntcUigeoce Laboratory Computer Science Department Univmity of California. Los Angeles</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>90024</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Dynamically-Adaptive Winner-Take-All Networks</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Winner-Take-All (WTA) networks. in which inhibitory interconnec-tions are used to determine the most highly-activated of a pool of unilS. are an important part of many neural network models. Unfortunately, convergence of normal WT A networks is extremely sensitive to the magnitudes of their weights, which must be hand-tuned and which generally only provide the right amount of inhibition across a relatively small range of initial conditions. This paper presents Dynamjcally-Adaptive Winner-Telke-All (DA WTA) netw&lt;rls, which use a regulatory unit to provide the competitive inhibition to the units in the network. The DA WT A regulatory unit dynamically adjusts its level of activation during competition to provide the right amount of inhibition to differentiate between competitors and drive a single winner. This dynamic adaptation allows DA WT A networks to perform the winner-lake-all function for nearly any network size or initial condition. using O(N) connections. In addition, the DA WT A regulaaory unit can be biased 10 find the level of inhibition necessary to settle upon the K most highly-activated units, and therefore serve as a K-Winners-Take-All network.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
