<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Useful Neighborhoods for Lazy Local Learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Aron</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
							<email>aron.yu@utexas.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Kristen</forename><surname>Grauman</surname></persName>
							<email>grauman@cs.utexas.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Predicting Useful Neighborhoods for Lazy Local Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Lazy local learning methods train a classifier &quot;on the fly&quot; at test time, using only a subset of the training instances that are most relevant to the novel test example. The goal is to tailor the classifier to the properties of the data surrounding the test example. Existing methods assume that the instances most useful for building the local model are strictly those closest to the test example. However, this fails to account for the fact that the success of the resulting classifier depends on the full distribution of selected training instances. Rather than simply gathering the test example&apos;s nearest neighbors, we propose to predict the subset of training data that is jointly relevant to training its local model. We develop an approach to discover patterns between queries and their &quot;good&quot; neighborhoods using large-scale multi-label classification with compressed sensing. Given a novel test point, we estimate both the composition and size of the training subset likely to yield an accurate local model. We demonstrate the approach on image classification tasks on SUN and aPascal and show its advantages over traditional global and local approaches.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
