<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Capturing Semantically Meaningful Word Dependencies with an Admixture of Poisson MRFs</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Inouye</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pradeep</forename><surname>Ravikumar</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Inderjit</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Dhillon</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Texas at Austin</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Capturing Semantically Meaningful Word Dependencies with an Admixture of Poisson MRFs</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We develop a fast algorithm for the Admixture of Poisson MRFs (APM) topic model [1] and propose a novel metric to directly evaluate this model. The APM topic model recently introduced by Inouye et al. [1] is the first topic model that allows for word dependencies within each topic unlike in previous topic models like LDA that assume independence between words within a topic. Research in both the semantic coherence of a topic models [2, 3, 4, 5] and measures of model fitness [6] provide strong support that explicitly modeling word dependencies-as in APM-could be both semantically meaningful and essential for appropriately modeling real text data. Though APM shows significant promise for providing a better topic model, APM has a high computational complexity because O(p 2) parameters must be estimated where p is the number of words ([1] could only provide results for datasets with p = 200). In light of this, we develop a parallel alternating Newton-like algorithm for training the APM model that can handle p = 10 4 as an important step towards scaling to large datasets. In addition, Inouye et al. [1] only provided tentative and inconclusive results on the utility of APM. Thus, motivated by simple intuitions and previous evaluations of topic models, we propose a novel evaluation metric based on human evocation scores between word pairs (i.e. how much one word &quot;brings to mind&quot; another word [7]). We provide compelling quantitative and qualitative results on the BNC corpus that demonstrate the superiority of APM over previous topic models for identifying semantically meaningful word dependencies. (MATLAB code available at:</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
