<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Structure learning of antiferromagnetic Ising models</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guy</forename><surname>Bresler</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of EECS</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory for Information and Decision Systems</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Sloan School of Management</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Gamarnik</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Massachusetts Institute of Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Devavrat</forename><surname>Shah</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Structure learning of antiferromagnetic Ising models</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper we investigate the computational complexity of learning the graph structure underlying a discrete undirected graphical model from i.i.d. samples. Our first result is an unconditional computational lower bound of (p d/2) for learning general graphical models on p nodes of maximum degree d, for the class of so-called statistical algorithms recently introduced by Feldman et al. [1]. The construction is related to the notoriously dicult learning parities with noise problem in computational learning theory. Our lower bound suggests that the Â O(p d+2) runtime required by Bresler, Mossel, and Sly&apos;s [2] exhaustive-search algorithm cannot be significantly improved without restricting the class of models. Aside from structural assumptions on the graph such as it being a tree, hypertree, tree-like, etc., many recent papers on structure learning assume that the model has the correlation decay property. Indeed, focusing on fer-romagnetic Ising models, Bento and Montanari [3] showed that all known low-complexity algorithms fail to learn simple graphs when the interaction strength exceeds a number related to the correlation decay threshold. Our second set of results gives a class of repelling (antiferromagnetic) models that have the opposite behavior: very strong interaction allows ecient learning in time Â O(p 2). We provide an algorithm whose performance interpolates between Â O(p 2) and Â O(p d+2) depending on the strength of the repulsion.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
