<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Provable Submodular Minimization using Wolfe&apos;s Algorithm</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Deeparnab</forename><surname>Chakrabarty</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Prateek</forename><surname>Jain</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pravesh</forename><surname>Kothari</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Provable Submodular Minimization using Wolfe&apos;s Algorithm</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Owing to several applications in large scale learning and vision problems, fast submodular function minimization (SFM) has become a critical problem. Theoretically , unconstrained SFM can be performed in polynomial time [10, 11]. However, these algorithms are typically not practical. In 1976, Wolfe [21] proposed an algorithm to find the minimum Euclidean norm point in a polytope, and in 1980, Fujishige [3] showed how Wolfe&apos;s algorithm can be used for SFM. For general submodular functions, this Fujishige-Wolfe minimum norm algorithm seems to have the best empirical performance. Despite its good practical performance, very little is known about Wolfe&apos;s minimum norm algorithm theoretically. To our knowledge, the only result is an exponential time analysis due to Wolfe [21] himself. In this paper we give a maiden convergence analysis of Wolfe&apos;s algorithm. We prove that in t iterations, Wolfe&apos;s algorithm returns an O(1/t)-approximate solution to the min-norm point on any polytope. We also prove a robust version of Fujishige&apos;s theorem which shows that an O(1/n 2)-approximate solution to the min-norm point on the base polytope implies exact submodular minimization. As a corollary, we get the first pseudo-polynomial time guarantee for the Fujishige-Wolfe minimum norm algorithm for unconstrained submodular function minimization.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
