<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:23+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Recovery of Coherent Data via Low-Rank Dictionary Pursuit</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Guangcan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
							<email>gcliu@rutgers.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Statistics and Biostatistics Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Statistics and Biostatistics Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Rutgers University Piscataway</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08854</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ping</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
							<email>pingli@rutgers.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Rutgers University Piscataway</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>08854</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Recovery of Coherent Data via Low-Rank Dictionary Pursuit</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The recently established RPCA [4] method provides a convenient way to restore low-rank matrices from grossly corrupted observations. While elegant in theory and powerful in reality, RPCA is not an ultimate solution to the low-rank matrix recovery problem. Indeed, its performance may not be perfect even when data are strictly low-rank. This is because RPCA ignores clustering structures of the data which are ubiquitous in applications. As the number of cluster grows, the coherence of data keeps increasing, and accordingly, the recovery performance of RPCA degrades. We show that the challenges raised by coherent data (i.e., data with high coherence) could be alleviated by Low-Rank Representation (LRR) [13], provided that the dictionary in LRR is configured appropriately. More precisely, we mathematically prove that if the dictionary itself is low-rank then LRR is immune to the coherence parameter which increases with the underlying cluster number. This provides an elementary principle for dealing with coherent data and naturally leads to a practical algorithm for obtaining proper dictionaries in unsupervised environments. Experiments on randomly generated matrices and real motion sequences verify our claims. See the full paper at arXiv:1404.4032.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
