<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:44+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">VISIT: A Neural Model of Covert Visual Attention</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Subutai</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">ZFE ST SN6</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Siemens Research and Development</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Otto-Hahn Ring 6, 8000 Munich 83</addrLine>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">VISIT: A Neural Model of Covert Visual Attention</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>420</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Visual attention is the ability to dynamically restrict processing to a subset of the visual field. Researchers have long argued that such a mechanism is necessary to efficiently perform many intermediate level visual tasks. This paper describes VISIT, a novel neural network model of visual attention. The current system models the search for target objects in scenes containing multiple distractors. This is a natural task for people, it is studied extensively by psychologists, and it requires attention. The network&apos;s behavior closely matches the known psychophysical data on visual search and visual attention. VISIT also matches much of the physiological data on attention and provides a novel view of the functionality of a number of visual areas. This paper concentrates on the biological plausibility of the model and its relationship to the primary visual cortex, pulvinar, superior colliculus and posterior parietal areas.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
