<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:44+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Spectral Clustering of Graphs with the Bethe Hessian</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Alaa</forename><surname>Saade</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Laboratoire de Physique Statistique</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">UMR 8550École 8550´8550École Normale Superieure</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">CNRS</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>24 Rue Lhomond Paris</addrLine>
									<postCode>75005</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Florent</forename><surname>Krzakala</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab1">Sorbonne Universités, UPMC Univ Paris 06</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory" key="lab2">Laboratoire de Physique Statistique, CNRS UMR 8550École 8550´8550École Normale Superieure</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>24 Rue Lhomond Paris</addrLine>
									<postCode>75005</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Lenka</forename><surname>Zdeborová</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Institut de Physique Théorique CEA Saclay and CNRS URA 2306</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91191</postCode>
									<settlement>Gif-sur-Yvette</settlement>
									<country key="FR">France</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Spectral Clustering of Graphs with the Bethe Hessian</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Spectral clustering is a standard approach to label nodes on a graph by studying the (largest or lowest) eigenvalues of a symmetric real matrix such as e.g. the adjacency or the Laplacian. Recently, it has been argued that using instead a more complicated, non-symmetric and higher dimensional operator, related to the non-backtracking walk on the graph, leads to improved performance in detecting clusters, and even to optimal performance for the stochastic block model. Here, we propose to use instead a simpler object, a symmetric real matrix known as the Bethe Hessian operator, or deformed Laplacian. We show that this approach combines the performances of the non-backtracking operator, thus detecting clusters all the way down to the theoretical limit in the stochastic block model, with the computational, theoretical and memory advantages of real symmetric matrices. Clustering a graph into groups or functional modules (sometimes called communities) is a central task in many fields ranging from machine learning to biology. A common benchmark for this problem is to consider graphs generated by the stochastic block model (SBM) [7, 22]. In this case, one considers n vertices and each of them has a group label g v ∈ {1,. .. , q}. A graph is then created as follows: all edges are generated independently according to a q × q matrix p of probabilities, with Pr[A u,v = 1] = p gu,gv. The group labels are hidden, and the task is to infer them from the knowledge of the graph. The stochastic block model generates graphs that are a generalization of the Erd˝ os-Rényi ensemble where an unknown labeling has been hidden. We concentrate on the sparse case, where algorithmic challenges appear. In this case p ab is O(1/n), and we denote p ab = c ab /n. For simplicity we concentrate on the most commonly-studied case where groups are equally sized, c ab = c in if a = b and c ab = c out if a = b. Fixing c in &gt; c out is referred to as the assortative case, because vertices from the same group connect with higher probability than with vertices from other groups. c out &gt; c in is called the disassortative case. An important conjecture [4] is that any tractable algorithm will only detect communities if |c in − c out | &gt; q √ c , (1) where c is the average degree. In the case of q = 2 groups, in particular, this has been rigorously proven [15, 12] (in this case, one can also prove that no algorithm could detect communities if this condition is not met). An ideal clustering algorithm should have a low computational complexity while being able to perform optimally for the stochastic block model, detecting clusters down to the transition (1).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
