<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:44+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">DISCOVERING STRUCfURE FROM MOTION IN MONKEY, MAN AND MACHINE</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Siegel·</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Laboratory of Neurobiology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">The Salk Institute of Biology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>La Jolla</addrLine>
									<postCode>92037</postCode>
									<region>Ca</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">The Rockefeller University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>1230 York Avenue</addrLine>
									<postCode>10021</postCode>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">DISCOVERING STRUCfURE FROM MOTION IN MONKEY, MAN AND MACHINE</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>701 The ability to obtain three-dimensional structure from visual motion is important for survival of human and non-human primates. Using a parallel processing model, the current work explores how the biological visual system might solve this problem and how the neurophysiologist might go about understanding the solution. INTRODUcnON Psychophysical experiments have shown that monke 1 and man are equally adept at obtaining three dimensional structure from motion. In the present work, much effort has been expended mimicking the visual system. This was done for one main reason: the model was designed to help direct physiological experiments in the primate. It was hoped that if an approach for understanding the model could be developed, the approach could then be directed at the primate&apos;s visual system. Early in this century, von Helmholtz 2 described the problem of extracting three-dimensional structure from motion: Suppose, for instance, that a person is standing still in a thick woods, where it is impossible for him to distinguish, except vaguely and roughly, in the mass of foliage and branches all around him what belongs to one tree and what to another, or how far apart the separate trees are, etc. But the moment he begins to move forward, everything disentangles itself, and immediately he gets an apperception of the material content of the woods and their relation to each other in space, just as if he were looking at a good stereoscopic view of it. If the object moves, rather than the observer, the perception of three-dimensional structure from motion is still obtained. Object-centered structure from motion is examined in this report. Lesion studies in monkey have demonstrated that two extra-striate visual cortices called the middle temporal area (abbreviated MT ·Current address:</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
