<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:45+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning Stationary Time Series using Gaussian Processes with Nonparametric Kernels</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Felipe</forename><surname>Tobar</surname></persName>
							<email>ftobar@dim.uchile.cl</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for Mathematical Modeling Universidad de Chile Thang D. Bui</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Cambridge</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for Mathematical Modeling Universidad de Chile Thang D. Bui</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Department of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">University of Cambridge</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Cambridge</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning Stationary Time Series using Gaussian Processes with Nonparametric Kernels</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We introduce the Gaussian Process Convolution Model (GPCM), a two-stage non-parametric generative procedure to model stationary signals as the convolution between a continuous-time white-noise process and a continuous-time linear filter drawn from Gaussian process. The GPCM is a continuous-time nonparametric-window moving average process and, conditionally, is itself a Gaussian process with a nonparametric kernel defined in a probabilistic fashion. The gen-erative model can be equivalently considered in the frequency domain, where the power spectral density of the signal is specified using a Gaussian process. One of the main contributions of the paper is to develop a novel variational free-energy approach based on inter-domain inducing variables that efficiently learns the continuous-time linear filter and infers the driving white-noise process. In turn, this scheme provides closed-form probabilistic estimates of the covariance kernel and the noise-free signal both in denoising and prediction scenarios. Additionally , the variational inference procedure provides closed-form expressions for the approximate posterior of the spectral density given the observed data, leading to new Bayesian nonparametric approaches to spectrum estimation. The proposed GPCM is validated using synthetic and real-world signals.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
