<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:45+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Bidirectional Recurrent Convolutional Networks for Multi-Frame Super-Resolution</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Center for Research on Intelligent Perception and Computing National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Center for Research on Intelligent Perception and Computing National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Center for Research on Intelligent Perception and Computing National Laboratory of Pattern Recognition</orgName>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Excellence in Brain Science and Intelligence Technology Institute of Automation</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Chinese Academy of Sciences</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Bidirectional Recurrent Convolutional Networks for Multi-Frame Super-Resolution</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Super resolving a low-resolution video is usually handled by either single-image super-resolution (SR) or multi-frame SR. Single-Image SR deals with each video frame independently, and ignores intrinsic temporal dependency of video frames which actually plays a very important role in video super-resolution. Multi-Frame SR generally extracts motion information, e.g., optical flow, to model the temporal dependency, which often shows high computational cost. Considering that recurrent neural networks (RNNs) can model long-term contextual information of temporal sequences well, we propose a bidirectional recurrent convolutional network for efficient multi-frame SR. Different from vanilla RNNs, 1) the commonly-used recurrent full connections are replaced with weight-sharing convolutional connections and 2) conditional convolutional connections from previous input layers to the current hidden layer are added for enhancing visual-temporal dependency modelling. With the powerful temporal dependency modelling, our model can super resolve videos with complex motions and achieve state-of-the-art performance. Due to the cheap convolution operations, our model has a low computational complexity and runs orders of magnitude faster than other multi-frame methods.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
