<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:45+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of distributed representation of constituent structure in connectionist systems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Smolensky</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Colorado</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>80309-0430</postCode>
									<settlement>Boulder</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of distributed representation of constituent structure in connectionist systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>730</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A general method, the tensor product representation, is described for the distributed representation of value/variable bindings. The method allows the fully distributed representation of symbolic structures: the roles in the structures, as well as the fillers for those roles, can be arbitrarily non-local. Fully and partially localized special cases reduce to existing cases of connectionist representations of structured data; the tensor product representation generalizes these and the few existing examples of fuUy distributed representations of structures. The representation saturates gracefully as larger structures are represented; it penn its recursive construction of complex representations from simpler ones; it respects the independence of the capacities to generate and maintain multiple bindings in parallel; it extends naturally to continuous structures and continuous representational patterns; it pennits values to also serve as variables; it enables analysis of the interference of symbolic structures stored in associative memories; and it leads to characterization of optimal distributed representations of roles and a recirculation algorithm for learning them.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
