<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:47+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Interaction Networks for Learning about Objects, Relations and Physics</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anonymous</forename><surname>Author</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Affiliation Address email</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Interaction Networks for Learning about Objects, Relations and Physics</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>15</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Reasoning about objects, relations, and physics is central to human intelligence, and 1 a key goal of artificial intelligence. Here we introduce the interaction network, a 2 model which can reason about how objects in complex systems interact, supporting 3 dynamical predictions, as well as inferences about the abstract properties of the 4 system. Our model takes graphs as input, performs object-and relation-centric 5 reasoning in a way that is analogous to a simulation, and is implemented using 6 deep neural networks. We evaluate its ability to reason about several challenging 7 physical domains: n-body problems, rigid-body collision, and non-rigid dynamics. 8 Our results show it can be trained to accurately simulate the physical trajectories of 9 dozens of objects over thousands of time steps, estimate abstract quantities such 10 as energy, and generalize automatically to systems with different numbers and 11 configurations of objects and relations. Our interaction network implementation 12 is the first general-purpose, learnable physics engine, and a powerful general 13 framework for reasoning about object and relations in a wide variety of complex 14 real-world domains.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
