<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:47+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Generalization of ERM in Stochastic Convex Optimization: The Dimension Strikes Back *</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Vitaly</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IBM Research -Almaden</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Generalization of ERM in Stochastic Convex Optimization: The Dimension Strikes Back *</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In stochastic convex optimization the goal is to minimize a convex function F (x). = Ef∼D[f (x)] over a convex set K ⊂ R d where D is some unknown distribution and each f (·) in the support of D is convex over K. The optimization is commonly based on i.i.d. samples f 1 , f 2 ,. .. , f n from D. A standard approach to such problems is empirical risk minimization (ERM) that optimizes F S (x). = 1 n i≤n f i (x). Here we consider the question of how many samples are necessary for ERM to succeed and the closely related question of uniform convergence of F S to F over K. We demonstrate that in the standard p // q setting of Lipschitz-bounded functions over a K of bounded radius, ERM requires sample size that scales linearly with the dimension d. This nearly matches standard upper bounds and improves on Ω(log d) dependence proved for 2 // 2 setting in [18]. In stark contrast, these problems can be solved using dimension-independent number of samples for 2 // 2 setting and log d dependence for 1 // ∞ setting using other approaches. We further show that our lower bound applies even if the functions in the support of D are smooth and efficiently computable and even if an 1 regularization term is added. Finally, we demonstrate that for a more general class of bounded-range (but not Lipschitz-bounded) stochastic convex programs an infinite gap appears already in dimension 2.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
