<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:47+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion Approximations for the Constant Learning Rate Backpropagation Algorithm and Resistence to Local Minima</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Finnoff</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Siemens AG, Corporate Research and Development Otto-Hahn-Ring</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>6 8000 Munich 83</addrLine>
									<country>Fed. Rep. Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Diffusion Approximations for the Constant Learning Rate Backpropagation Algorithm and Resistence to Local Minima</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>In this paper we discuss the asymptotic properties of the most commonly used variant of the backpropagation algorithm in which network weights are trained by means of a local gradient descent on examples drawn randomly from a fixed training set, and the learning rate TJ of the gradient updates is held constant (simple backpropa-gation). Using stochastic approximation results, we show that for TJ ~ 0 this training process approaches a batch training and provide results on the rate of convergence. Further, we show that for small TJ one can approximate simple back propagation by the sum of a batch training process and a Gaussian diffusion which is the unique solution to a linear stochastic differential equation. Using this approximation we indicate the reasons why simple backprop-agation is less likely to get stuck in local minima than the batch training process and demonstrate this empirically on a number of examples.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
