<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:48+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">ON PROPERTIES OF NETWORKS OF NEURON-LIKE ELEMENTS</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
				<date type="published" when="1987-12-15">15 December 1987</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Baldi·</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Santosh</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Venkatesh</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">ON PROPERTIES OF NETWORKS OF NEURON-LIKE ELEMENTS</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date type="published" when="1987-12-15">15 December 1987</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The complexity and computational capacity of multi-layered, feedforward neural networks is examined. Neural networks for special purpose (structured) functions are examined from the perspective of circuit complexity. Known results in complexity theory are applied to the special instance of neural network circuits, and in particular, classes of functions that can be implemented in shallow circuits characterised. Some conclusions are also drawn about learning complexity, and some open problems raised. The dual problem of determining the computational capacity of a class of multi-layered networks with dynamics regulated by an algebraic Hamiltonian is considered. Formal results are presented on the storage capacities of programmed higher-order structures, and a tradeoff between ease of programming and capacity is shown. A precise determination is made of the static fixed point structure of random higher-order constructs, and phase-transitions (0-1 laws) are shown.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
