<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:48+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Best of Both Worlds: Transferring Knowledge from Discriminative Learning to a Generative Visual Dialog Model</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jiasen</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2 Curai</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Anitha</forename><surname>Kannan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Jianwei</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2 Curai</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Devi</forename><surname>Parikh</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2 Curai</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Facebook AI Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Dhruv</forename><surname>Batra</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2 Curai</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Facebook AI Research</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Best of Both Worlds: Transferring Knowledge from Discriminative Learning to a Generative Visual Dialog Model</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We present a novel training framework for neural sequence models, particularly for grounded dialog generation. The standard training paradigm for these models is maximum likelihood estimation (MLE), or minimizing the cross-entropy of the human responses. Across a variety of domains, a recurring problem with MLE trained generative neural dialog models (G) is that they tend to produce &apos;safe&apos; and generic responses (&apos;I don&apos;t know&apos;, &apos;I can&apos;t tell&apos;). In contrast, discriminative dialog models (D) that are trained to rank a list of candidate human responses outperform their generative counterparts; in terms of automatic metrics, diversity, and informativeness of the responses. However, D is not useful in practice since it can not be deployed to have real conversations with users. Our work aims to achieve the best of both worlds-the practical usefulness of G and the strong performance of D-via knowledge transfer from D to G. Our primary contribution is an end-to-end trainable generative visual dialog model, where G receives gradients from D as a perceptual (not adversarial) loss of the sequence sampled from G. We leverage the recently proposed Gumbel-Softmax (GS) approximation to the discrete distribution-specifically, a RNN augmented with a sequence of GS samplers, coupled with the straight-through gradient estimator to enable end-to-end differentiability. We also introduce a stronger encoder for visual dialog, and employ a self-attention mechanism for answer encoding along with a metric learning loss to aid D in better capturing semantic similarities in answer responses. Overall, our proposed model outperforms state-of-the-art on the VisDial dataset by a significant margin (2.67% on recall@10).</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
