<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:48+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Deriving Receptive Fields Using An Optimal Encoding Criterion</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ralph</forename><surname>Linsker</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">IBM T. J. Watson Research Center</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P. O. Box 218</postBox>
									<postCode>10598</postCode>
									<settlement>Yorktown Heights</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Deriving Receptive Fields Using An Optimal Encoding Criterion</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>An information-theoretic optimization principle (&apos;infomax&apos;) has previously been used for unsupervised learning of statistical regularities in an input ensemble. The principle states that the input-output mapping implemented by a processing stage should be chosen so as to maximize the average mutual information between input and output patterns, subject to constraints and in the presence of processing noise. In the present work I show how infomax, when applied to a class of nonlinear input-output mappings, can under certain conditions generate optimal filters that have additional useful properties: (1) Output activity (for each input pattern) tends to be concentrated among a relatively small number of nodes. (2) The filters are sensitive to higher-order statistical structure (beyond pairwise correlations). If the input features are localized, the filters&apos; receptive fields tend to be localized as well. (3) Multiresolution sets of filters with subsampling at low spatial frequencies-related to pyramid coding and wavelet representations-emerge as favored solutions for certain types of input ensembles.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
