<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:49+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Universal Analysis of Large-Scale Regularized Least Squares Solutions</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ashkan</forename><surname>Panahi</surname></persName>
							<email>apanahi@ncsu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering North</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Electrical Engineering California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carolina State University Raleigh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>27606, 91125</postCode>
									<region>NC, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Babak</forename><surname>Hassibi</surname></persName>
							<email>hassibi@caltech.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering North</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Electrical Engineering California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carolina State University Raleigh</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>27606, 91125</postCode>
									<region>NC, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Universal Analysis of Large-Scale Regularized Least Squares Solutions</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>A problem that has been of recent interest in statistical inference, machine learning and signal processing is that of understanding the asymptotic behavior of regular-ized least squares solutions under random measurement matrices (or dictionaries). The Least Absolute Shrinkage and Selection Operator (LASSO or least-squares with 1 regularization) is perhaps one of the most interesting examples. Precise expressions for the asymptotic performance of LASSO have been obtained for a number of different cases, in particular when the elements of the dictionary matrix are sampled independently from a Gaussian distribution. It has also been empirically observed that the resulting expressions remain valid when the entries of the dictionary matrix are independently sampled from certain non-Gaussian distributions. In this paper, we confirm these observations theoretically when the distribution is sub-Gaussian. We further generalize the previous expressions for a broader family of regularization functions and under milder conditions on the underlying random, possibly non-Gaussian, dictionary matrix. In particular, we establish the universality of the asymptotic statistics (e.g., the average quadratic risk) of LASSO with non-Gaussian dictionaries.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
