<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:49+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">On the Power of Neural Networks for Solving Hard Problems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ehoshua Bruck</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departmen t of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Systems Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University Stanford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Departmen t of Electrical Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Information Systems Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University Stanford</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94305</postCode>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">On the Power of Neural Networks for Solving Hard Problems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper deals with a neural network model in which each neuron performs a threshold logic function. An important property of the model is that it always converges to a stable state when operating in a serial mode [2,5]. This property is the basis of the potential applications of the model such as associative memory devices and combinatorial optimization [3,6]. One of the motivations for use of the model for solving hard combinatorial problems is the fact that it can be implemented by optical devices and thus operate at a higher speed than conventional electronics. The main theme in this work is to investigate the power of the model for solving NP-hard problems [4,8], and to understand the relation between speed of operation and the size of a neural network. In particular, it will be shown that for any NP-hard problem the existence of a polynomial size network that solves it implies that NP=co-NP. Also, for Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP), even a polynomial size network that gets an €-approximate solution does not exist unless P=NP. The above results are of great practical interest, because right now it is possible to build neural networks which will operate fast but are limited in the number of neurons. 1 Background 137 The neural network model is a discrete time system that can be represented by a weighted and undirected graph. There is a weight attached to each edge of the graph and a threshold value attached to each node (neuron) of the graph.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
