<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:49+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Is Input Sparsity Time Possible for Kernel Low-Rank Approximation?</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Cameron</forename><surname>Musco</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Woodruff</surname></persName>
							<email>dwoodruf@cs.cmu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Is Input Sparsity Time Possible for Kernel Low-Rank Approximation?</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Low-rank approximation is a common tool used to accelerate kernel methods: the n ⇥ n kernel matrix K is approximated via a rank-k matrix˜Kmatrix˜ matrix˜K which can be stored in much less space and processed more quickly. In this work we study the limits of computationally efficient low-rank kernel approximation. We show that for a broad class of kernels, including the popular Gaussian and polynomial kernels, computing a relative error k-rank approximation to K is at least as difficult as multiplying the input data matrix A 2 R n⇥d by an arbitrary matrix C 2 R d⇥k. Barring a breakthrough in fast matrix multiplication, when k is not too large, this requires ⌦(nnz(A)k) time where nnz(A) is the number of non-zeros in A. This lower bound matches, in many parameter regimes, recent work on subquadratic time algorithms for low-rank approximation of general kernels [MM16, MW17], demonstrating that these algorithms are unlikely to be significantly improved, in particular to O(nnz(A)) input sparsity runtimes. At the same time there is hope: we show for the first time that O(nnz(A)) time approximation is possible for general radial basis function kernels (e.g., the Gaussian kernel) for the closely related problem of low-rank approximation of the kernelized dataset.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
