<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A KL-LUCB Bandit Algorithm for Large-Scale Crowdsourcing 1 Multi-Armed Bandits for Large-Scale Crowdsourcing</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ervin</forename><surname>Tánczos</surname></persName>
							<email>tanczos@wisc.edu, rdnowak@wisc.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Nowak</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bob</forename><surname>Mankoff</surname></persName>
							<email>bmankoff@hearst.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Wisconsin-Madison</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A KL-LUCB Bandit Algorithm for Large-Scale Crowdsourcing 1 Multi-Armed Bandits for Large-Scale Crowdsourcing</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>Former Cartoon Editor of the New Yorker 3 For more details on the New Yorker Cartoon Caption Contest, see the Supplementary Materials. 31st Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS 2017), Long Beach, CA, USA.</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper focuses on best-arm identification in multi-armed bandits with bounded rewards. We develop an algorithm that is a fusion of lil-UCB and KL-LUCB, offering the best qualities of the two algorithms in one method. This is achieved by proving a novel anytime confidence bound for the mean of bounded distributions, which is the analogue of the LIL-type bounds recently developed for sub-Gaussian distributions. We corroborate our theoretical results with numerical experiments based on the New Yorker Cartoon Caption Contest. This paper develops a new multi-armed bandit (MAB) for large-scale crowdsourcing, in the style of the KL-UCB [4, 9, 3]. Our work is strongly motivated by crowdsourcing contests, like the New Yorker Cartoon Caption contest [10] 3. The new approach targets the &quot;best-arm identification problem&quot; [1] in the fixed confidence setting and addresses two key limitations of existing theory and algorithms: (i) State of the art algorithms for best arm identification are based on sub-Gaussian confidence bounds [5] and fail to exploit the fact that rewards are usually bounded in crowdsourcing applications. (ii) Existing KL-UCB algorithms for best-arm identification do exploit bounded rewards [8] , but have suboptimal performance guarantees in the fixed confidence setting, both in terms of dependence on problem-dependent hardness parameters (Chernoff information) and on the number of arms, which can be large in crowdsourcing applications. The new algorithm we propose and analyze is called lil-KLUCB, since it is inspired by the lil-UCB algorithm [5] and the KL-LUCB algorithm [8]. The lil-UCB algorithm is based on sub-Gaussian bounds and has a sample complexity for best-arm identification that scales as i≥2 ∆ −2 i log(δ −1 log ∆ −2 i) , where δ ∈ (0, 1) is the desired confidence and ∆ i = µ 1 − µ i is the gap between the means of the best arm (denoted as arm 1) and arm i. If the rewards are in [0, 1], then the KL-LUCB algorithm has †</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
