<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">What Does the Hippocampus Compute?: A Precis of the 1993 NIPS Workshop</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gluck</surname></persName>
							<email>gluck@pavlov.rutgers.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Molecular and Behavioral</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Neuroscience Rutgers University Newark</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>07102</postCode>
									<region>NJ</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">What Does the Hippocampus Compute?: A Precis of the 1993 NIPS Workshop</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Computational models of the hippocampal-region provide an important method for understanding the functional role of this brain system in learning and memory. The presentations in this workshop focused on how modeling can lead to a unified understanding of the interplay among hippocampal physiology, anatomy, and behavior. Several approaches were presented. One approach can be characterized as &quot;top-down&quot; analyses of the neuropsychology of memory, drawing upon brain-lesion studies in animals and humans. Other models take a &quot;bottom-up&quot; approach, seeking to infer emergent computational and functional properties from detailed analyses of circuit connectivity and physiology (see Gluck &amp; Granger, 1993, for a review). Among the issues discussed were: (1) integration of physiological and behavioral theories of hippocampal function, (2) similarities and differences between animal and human studies, (3) representational vs. temporal properties of hippocampal-dependent behaviors, (4) rapid vs. incremental learning, (5) mUltiple vs. unitary memory systems, (5) spatial navigation and memory, and (6) hippocampal interaction with other brain systems. Jay McClelland, of Carnegie-Mellon University, presented one example of a top-down approach to theory development in his talk, &quot;Complementary roles of neocortex and hippocampus in learning and memory&quot; McClelland reviewed findings indicating that the hippocampus appears necessary for the initial acquisition of some forms of memory, but that ultimately all forms of memory are stored independently of the hippocampal system. Consolidation in the neocortex appears to occur over an extended period-in humans the process appears to extend over several years. McClelland suggested that the cortex uses interleaved learning to extract the structure of events and experiences while the hippocampus provides a special system for the rapid initial storage of traces of specific events and experiences in a form that minimizes mutual interference between memory traces. According to this view, the hippocampus is necessary to avoid the catastrophic 1173</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
