<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Invariant Object Recognition Using a Distributed Associative Memory</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Wechsler</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department or Electrical</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Engineering University or Minnesota Minneapolis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>55455</postCode>
									<region>MN</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">Lee</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department or Electrical</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Engineering University or Minnesota Minneapolis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>55455</postCode>
									<region>MN</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Invariant Object Recognition Using a Distributed Associative Memory</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<note>830</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper describes an approach to 2-dimensional object recognition. Complex-log con-formal mapping is combined with a distributed associative memory to create a system which recognizes objects regardless of changes in rotation or scale. Recalled information from the memorized database is used to classify an object, reconstruct the memorized version of the object, and estimate the magnitude of changes in scale or rotation. The system response is resistant to moderate amounts of noise and occlusion. Several experiments, using real, gray scale images, are presented to show the feasibility of our approach. Introduction The challenge of the visual recognition problem stems from the fact that the projection of an object onto an image can be confounded by several dimensions of variability such as uncertain perspective, changing orientation and scale, sensor noise, occlusion, and non-uniform illumination. A vision system must not only be able to sense the identity of an object despite this variability, but must also be able to characterize such variability-because the variability inherently carries much of the valuable information about the world. Our goal is to derive the functional characteristics of image representations suitable for invariant recognition using a distributed associative memory. The main question is that of finding appropriate transformations such that interactions between the internal structure of the resulting representations and the distributed associative memory yield invariant recognition. As Simon [1] points out, all mathematical derivation can be viewed simply as a change of representation, making evident what was previously true but obscure. This view can be extended to all problem solving. Solving a problem then means transforming it so as to make the solution transparent .</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
