<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Functional Models of Selective Attention and Context Dependency</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Hildebrandt</surname></persName>
							<email>thildebr@aragorn.eecs.lehigh.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Room</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Lehigh University Bethlehem PA</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>304 Packard Laboratory 19 Memorial Drive West</addrLine>
									<postCode>18015-3084</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Functional Models of Selective Attention and Context Dependency</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Scope This workshop reviewed and classified the various models which have emerged from the general concept of selective attention and context dependency, and sought to identify their commonalities. It was concluded that the motivation and mechanism of these functional models are &quot;efficiency&quot; and &apos;&apos;factoring&apos;&apos;, respectively. The workshop focused on computational models of selective attention and context dependency within the realm of neural networks. We treated only &apos;&apos;functional&apos;&apos; models ; computational models of biological neural systems, and symbolic or rule-based systems were omitted from the discussion. Presentations Thomas H. Hildebrandt presented the results of his recent survey of the literature on functional models of selective attention and context dependency. He set forth the notions that selective attention and context dependency are equivalent , that the goal of these methods is to reduce computational requirements, and that this goal is achieved by what amounts to factoring or a divide-and-conquer technique which takes advantage of nonlinearities in the problem. Daniel S. Levine (University of Texas at Arlington) showed how the gated dipole structure often used in the ART models can be used to account for time-dependent phenomena such as habituation and overcompensation. His adjusted model appropriately modelled the public&apos;s adverse reaction to &quot;New Coke&quot;. Lev Goldfarb (University of New Brunswick) presented a formal model for in-ductive learning based on symbolic transformation systems and parametric distance functions as an alternative to the commonly used algebraic transformation system and Euclidean distance function. The drawbacks of the latter system were briefly discussed, and it was shown how this new formal system can give rise to learning models which overcome these problems. 1180</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
