<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Neurobiology, Psychophysics, and Computational Models of Visual Attention</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Ernst</forename><surname>Niebur</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computation and Neural Systems California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology Washington University School of Medicine St. Louis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91125, 63110</postCode>
									<region>CA, MO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Olshausen</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computation and Neural Systems California Institute of Technology Pasadena</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology Washington University School of Medicine St. Louis</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>91125, 63110</postCode>
									<region>CA, MO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Neurobiology, Psychophysics, and Computational Models of Visual Attention</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The purpose of this workshop was to discuss both recent experimental findings and computational models of the neurobiological implementation of selective attention. Recent experimental results were presented in two of the four presentations given (C.E. Connor, Washington University and B.C. Motter, SUNY and V.A. Medical Center, Syracuse), while the other two talks were devoted to computational models (E. Niebur, Caltech, and B. Olshausen, Washington University). Connor presented the results of an experiment in which the receptive field profiles of V 4 neurons were mapped during different states of attention in an awake, behaving monkey. The attentional focus was manipulated in this experiment by altering the position of a behaviorally relevant ring-shaped stimulus. The animal&apos;s task was to judge the size of the ring when compared to a reference ring (i.e., same or different). In order to map the receptive field profile, a behaviorally irrelevant bar stimulus was flashed at one of several positions inside and outside the classical receptive field (CRF). It was found that shifts of attention produced alterations in receptive field profiles for over half the cells studied. In most cases the receptive field center of gravity translated towards attentional foci in or near the CRF. Changes in width and shape of the receptive field profile were also observed, but responsive regions were not typically limited to the location of the attended ring stimulus. Attention-related effects often included enhanced responses at certain locations as well as diminished responses at other locations. Motter studied the basic mechanisms of visual search as manifested in the single unit activity of rhesus monkeys. The animals were trained to select a bar stimulus among others based on the color or luminance of the target stimulus. The majority of neurons were selectively activated when the color or luminance of the stimulus in the receptive field matched the color or luminance of the cue, whereas the activity was attenuated when there was no match. Since a cell responds differently to the same stimulus depending on the color or luminance of the cue (which is given far away from the stimulus by the color or luminance of the fixation spot), the activity of the neurons reflect a selection based on the cued feature and not simply the physical color or luminance of the receptive field stimulus. Motter showed that the 1167</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
