<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Learning Classification with Unlabeled Data</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Virginia</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>De Sa</surname></persName>
							<email>desa@cs.rochester.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Rochester Rochester</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>14627</postCode>
									<region>NY</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Learning Classification with Unlabeled Data</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>One of the advantages of supervised learning is that the final error metric is available during training. For classifiers, the algorithm can directly reduce the number of misclassifications on the training set. Unfortunately , when modeling human learning or constructing classifiers for autonomous robots, supervisory labels are often not available or too expensive. In this paper we show that we can substitute for the labels by making use of structure between the pattern distributions to different sensory modalities. We show that minimizing the disagreement between the outputs of networks processing patterns from these different modalities is a sensible approximation to minimizing the number of misclassifications in each modality, and leads to similar results. Using the Peterson-Barney vowel dataset we show that the algorithm performs well in finding appropriate placement for the codebook vectors particularly when the con-fuseable classes are different for the two modalities.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
