<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Correlation Functions in a Large Stochastic Neural Network</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Iris</forename><surname>Ginzburg</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">School of Physics and Astronomy Raymond</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Neural Computation Hebrew University Jerusalem 91904</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>69978</postCode>
									<country>Israel, Israel</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Correlation Functions in a Large Stochastic Neural Network</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Most theoretical investigations of large recurrent networks focus on the properties of the macroscopic order parameters such as population averaged activities or average overlaps with memories. However , the statistics of the fluctuations in the local activities may be an important testing ground for comparison between models and observed cortical dynamics. We evaluated the neuronal correlation functions in a stochastic network comprising of excitatory and inhibitory populations. We show that when the network is in a stationary state, the cross-correlations are relatively weak, i.e., their amplitude relative to that of the auto-correlations are of order of 1/ N, N being the size of the interacting population. This holds except in the neighborhoods of bifurcations to nonstationary states. As a bifurcation point is approached the amplitude of the cross-correlations grows and becomes of order 1 and the decay time-constant diverges. This behavior is analogous to the phenomenon of critical slowing down in systems at thermal equilibrium near a critical point. Near a Hopf bifurcation the cross-correlations exhibit damped oscillations. 471 472 Ginzburg and Sompolinsky</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
