<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">SPONTANEOUS AND INFORMATION-TRIGGERED SEGMENTS OF SERIES OF HUMAN BRAIN ELECTRIC FIELD MAPS 467</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lehmann</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Neurol09Y Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University Hospital</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8091</postCode>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Brandeis</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Neurol09Y Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University Hospital</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8091</postCode>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Horst</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Neurol09Y Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University Hospital</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8091</postCode>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ozaki</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Neurol09Y Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University Hospital</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8091</postCode>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Pal</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Neurol09Y Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University Hospital</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>8091</postCode>
									<settlement>Zurich</settlement>
									<country key="CH">Switzerland</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">SPONTANEOUS AND INFORMATION-TRIGGERED SEGMENTS OF SERIES OF HUMAN BRAIN ELECTRIC FIELD MAPS 467</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>The brain works in a state-dependent manner: processin9 strate9ies and access to stored information depends on the momentary functional state which is continuously readjusted. The state is manifest as spatial confi9uration of the brain electric field. Spontaneous and information-tri9gered brain electric activity is a series of momentary field maps. Adaptive segmentation of spontaneous series into spatially stable epochs (states) exhibited 210 msec mean segments, discontinuous changes. Different maps imply different active neural populations, hence expectedly different effects on information processing: Reaction time differred between map classes at stimulus arrival. Segments might be units of brain information processin9 (content/mode/step), possibly operationalizin9 consciousness time. Related units (e.9. tri9gered by stimuli durin9 fi9ure perception and voluntary attention) mi9ht specify brain sub-mechanisms of information treatment. BRAIN FUNCTIONAL STATES AND THEIR CHANGES The momentary functional state of the brain is reflected by the confi9uration of the brain&apos;s electro-ma9netic field. The state manifests the strate9Y, mode, step and content of brain information processing, and the state constrains the choice of strate9ies and modes and the access to memory material available for processin9 of incoming information (1). The constraints include the available range of changes of state in PAVLOV&apos;s classical ·orienting reaction&quot; as response to new or important informations. Different states mi9ht be viewed as different functional connectivities between the neural elements. The orienting reaction (see 1,2) is the result of the first (Mpre-attentiveM) stage of information processing. This stage operates automatically (no involvement of consciousness) and in a parallel mode, and quickly determines whether (a) the information is important or unknown and hence requires increased attention and alertness, i.e. an orienting reaction which means a readjustment of functional state in order to deal adequately with the information invokin9 consciousness for further processing, or whether (b) the information is known or unimportant and hence requires no readjustment of state, i.e. that it can be treated further with well-* Present addresses: D.B. at Psychiat. Dept., V.A. Med. Center, San Francisco CA 94121; H.O. at lab. Physiol. for the Developmentally Handicapped, Ibaraki Univ., Mito, Japan 310; I.P. at Biol09ic Systems Corp., Mundelein Il 60060.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
