<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Monte Carlo Matrix Inversion and Reinforcement Learning</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Barto</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Massachusetts Amherst</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>01003</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Duff</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Massachusetts Amherst</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>01003</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Monte Carlo Matrix Inversion and Reinforcement Learning</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>We describe the relationship between certain reinforcement learning (RL) methods based on dynamic programming (DP) and a class of unorthodox Monte Carlo methods for solving systems of linear equations proposed in the 1950&apos;s. These methods recast the solution of the linear system as the expected value of a statistic suitably defined over sample paths of a Markov chain. The significance of our observations lies in arguments (Curtiss, 1954) that these Monte Carlo methods scale better with respect to state-space size than do standard, iterative techniques for solving systems of linear equations. This analysis also establishes convergence rate estimates. Because methods used in RL systems for approximating the evaluation function of a fixed control policy also approximate solutions to systems of linear equations, the connection to these Monte Carlo methods establishes that algorithms very similar to TD algorithms (Sutton, 1988) are asymptotically more efficient in a precise sense than other methods for evaluating policies. Further, all DP-based RL methods have some of the properties of these Monte Carlo algorithms , which suggests that although RL is often perceived to be slow, for sufficiently large problems, it may in fact be more efficient than other known classes of methods capable of producing the same results. 687 688 Barto and Duff</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
