<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:50+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">JPMAX: Learning to Recognize Moving Objects as a Model-fitting Problem</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Suzanna</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">McMaster University Hamilton</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>L8S 4K1</postCode>
									<region>Onto</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">JPMAX: Learning to Recognize Moving Objects as a Model-fitting Problem</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Unsupervised learning procedures have been successful at low-level feature extraction and preprocessing of raw sensor data. So far, however, they have had limited success in learning higher-order representations, e.g., of objects in visual images. A promising approach is to maximize some measure of agreement between the outputs of two groups of units which receive inputs physically separated in space, time or modality, as in (Becker and Hinton, 1992; Becker, 1993; de Sa, 1993). Using the same approach, a much simpler learning procedure is proposed here which discovers features in a single-layer network consisting of several populations of units, and can be applied to multi-layer networks trained one layer at a time. When trained with this algorithm on image sequences of moving geometric objects a two-layer network can learn to perform accurate position-invariant object classification. 1 LEARNING COHERENT CLASSIFICATIONS A powerful constraint in sensory data is coherence over time, in space, and across different sensory modalities. An unsupervised learning procedure which can capitalize on these constraints may be able to explain much of perceptual self-organization in the mammalian brain. The problem is to derive an appropriate cost function for unsupervised learning which will capture coherence constraints in sensory signals; we would also like it to be applicable to multi-layer nets to train hidden as well as output layers. Our ultimate goal is for the network to discover natural object classes based on these coherence assumptions.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
