<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:51+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Grammar Learning by a Self-Organizing Network</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Michiro</forename><surname>Negishi</surname></persName>
							<email>email: negishi@cns.bu.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Cognitive and Neural Systems</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Boston University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>111 Cummington Street Boston</addrLine>
									<postCode>02215</postCode>
									<region>MA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Grammar Learning by a Self-Organizing Network</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>This paper presents the design and simulation results of a self-organizing neural network which induces a grammar from example sentences. Input sentences are generated from a simple phrase structure grammar including number agreement, verb transitiv-ity, and recursive noun phrase construction rules. The network induces a grammar explicitly in the form of symbol categorization rules and phrase structure rules. 1 Purpose and related works The purpose of this research is to show that a self-organizing network with a certain structure can acquire syntactic knowledge from only positive (i.e. grammatical) data, without requiring any initial knowledge or external teachers that correct errors. There has been research on supervised neural network models of language acquisition tasks [Elman, 1991, Miikkulainen and Dyer, 1988, John and McClelland, 1988]. Unlike these supervised models, the current model self-organizes word and phrasal categories and phrase construction rules through mere exposure to input sentences, without any artificially defined task goals. There also have been self-organizing models of language acquisition tasks [Ritter and Kohonen, 1990, Scholtes, 1991]. Compared to these models, the current model acquires phrase structure rules in more explicit forms, and it learns wider and more structured contexts, as will be explained below.</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
