<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 /Users/melina/Documents/js/scrape/grobid/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.5.1-SNAPSHOT" ident="GROBID" when="2018-02-21T06:51+0000">
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid">GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</ref>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Grouping Components of Three-Dimensional Moving Objects Area MST of Visual Cortex</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Zemel</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The Salk Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 85800</postBox>
									<postCode>15213, 92186-5800</postCode>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>PA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><forename type="first">Terrence</forename><forename type="middle">J Sejnowski</forename><surname>Cnl</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Psychology Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">The Salk Institute</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.O. Box 85800</postBox>
									<postCode>15213, 92186-5800</postCode>
									<settlement>San Diego</settlement>
									<region>PA, CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Grouping Components of Three-Dimensional Moving Objects Area MST of Visual Cortex</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
				<p>Many cells in the dorsal part of the medial superior temporal (MST) area of visual cortex respond selectively to spiral flow patterns-specific combinations of expansion/ contraction and rotation motions. Previous investigators have suggested that these cells may represent self-motion. Spiral patterns can also be generated by the relative motion of the observer and a particular object. An MST cell may then account for some portion of the complex flow field, and the set of active cells could encode the entire flow; in this manner, MST effectively segments moving objects. Such a grouping operation is essential in interpreting scenes containing several independent moving objects and observer motion. We describe a model based on the hypothesis that the selective tuning of MST cells reflects the grouping of object components undergoing coherent motion. Inputs to the model were generated from sequences of ray-traced images that simulated realistic motion situations , combining observer motion, eye movements, and independent object motion. The input representation was modeled after response properties of neurons in area MT, which provides the primary input to area MST. After applying an unsupervised learning algorithm, the units became tuned to patterns signaling coherent motion. The results match many of the known properties of MST cells and are consistent with recent studies indicating that these cells process 3-D object motion information. • In 166 Richard S. Zemel, Terrence J. Sejnowski</p>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
	</text>
</TEI>
